-能麻┠阍谶@Y名幔 -好的
- Can I get you to sign right here, please? - Okay. Here you go.
-xx -不客
-Thanks. -You're welcome.
(FOOTSTEPS PATTERING)
嗨，  威，  你的包裹
Hi, Will. Package for you.
(PEN CLICKING)
我想]有人能在自己的婚Yr想像
I don't think anyone ever imagines on their wedding day
他是那46% ]有^幸福快返纳活族群
be part of the 46% that doesn't live happily ever after.
x婚C
威？
Will?
f我拿到了桂格片的合s
Just heard we got the Quaker Oats account.
值煤茫  你一定很_心吧
Way to go. You must be completely psyched.
又f回
Then again,
我奈聪脒^
I never thought I'd spend my days,
我年鸵荒甑奶V告公司u命
weeks and years working in an advertising agency
每天在@Y想如何哄_ 小孩子吃某牌子的片
trying to figure out how to get kids to eat Cap'n Crunch instead of Froot Loops.
但星期二c星期五是我最鄣娜兆
But Tuesdays and Fridays are my favorite days.
可以提早下班 可以接我女含雅放W
I get out of work early, and I go pick up my daughter, Maya, from school.
找到能搭配一天心情的歌感X真好
Now, it's a great feeling when you find the right track to go with the day.
我今天可找到了最恰的歌
And today, I have found the absolute perfect song.
(HIP HOP MUSIC PLAYING)
婊子，  她可H我的
Bitches, they can kiss my...
是另一首恰的歌
The other perfect song.
(EVERYDAY PEOPLE PLAYING)
|51街
迪d街
(CAR HORN BLARING)
xx
(MOUTHING WORDS) Thank you.
不客
You're welcome.
R\！急需$$修理太空船 返回WD星球
xx！
有r不管你多小心的排曲目
But sometimes, no matter how carefully you plan your playlist,
哈德森梅瑞小W
都找不到一首m合下r的歌
there is no right track for what awaits you.
(ALL CLAMORING)
-走了，  走了！ -嘿，  l生什N事？
-Come on, come on! -Hey, what's going on?
威，  你知道今天有健康教育n幔
Will, did you know there was gonna be a sex ed class today?
他太小了吧？
Aren't they kind of young?
-β铮≌媸碾y -最起a他_始x
-Yeah! It was a total disaster. -At least it got them reading.
有耶！
There's a book!
「2|5千f精子射出
"The 250 million sperm are ejaculated
「展_了他 前往卵管U旱穆猛荆
"and begin their treacherous journey towards the fallopian tubes!
「有一|f即刻死亡…
"One hundred million are wiped out instantly..."
我要去找雅
I'm gonna find Maya.
你跟爸爸做幔
GlRL: Do you still have sex with Daddy?
-你在f什N？ -有幔
-What are you talking about? -Do you?
-我回家… -你有，  Π桑
-You know, we will go home and talk... -You do, don't you?
-我回家再@ -我恨你、我恨你！
-We will go home and talk about this. -GlRL: I hate you, I hate you!
(CLAMORING CONTINUES)
e拉我！我要弄清楚真相！
Stop pulling on me! I am trying to get to the bottom of something!
我得
We need to talk.
就是一男人⑺的生殖器 乃中掏出
Which is when the man removes his penis from his pajamas
K插入一女人的道…
and thrusts it into a woman's vagina...
好的，  但葛R格老 K]有f「插入」
Okay, but Mrs. Gallagher didn't actually say "thrust."
有啊
-Yeah. -Oh.
我不懂的是
But what I don't understand,
山米柏根的姐姐f他是意外
Sammy Boigon's sister said he was an accident.
你怎能不小心的⑸殖器插入… 嗨，  路易士
I mean, how do you accidentally thrust a penis into... Hi, Luis.
-嘿 -你怎能不小心的…
-Hey. -How do you accidentally...
停止f「生殖器」c「插入」 就f「uu的地方」或是「弟弟」
Stop saying "penis" and "thrust." Just say "tinkle part" or "wee-wee."
可埸c的
Something cute.
-解山米槭颤N是意外 -那很}s
-Explain how Sammy was an accident. -That's complicated.
-生殖器！生殖器 -好了，  蛄
-Penis! Penis. -Okay. All right, that's enough.
好的，  他…
(SIGHING) Okay, they...
他爸又不是踩到香蕉皮
It's not like his dad slipped on a banana peel.
意外是山米的蚜嗽
The accident was that Sammy's mom got pregnant.
他若不想要小孩槭颤N要做郏
If they didn't want a baby, then how come they had sex?
@}很好
That's a very good question.
可以f他是在排
I guess you could say that they were rehearsing.
-我也是意外幔 -不
-Was I an accident? -No.
-我是，  幔 -不
-I was, wasn't I? -No.
你^κ枪室獾 我非常清楚l生了什N事
You were completely and totally on purpose. I knew exactly what I was getting into.
(SIGHS)
易碎品 小心搬\
我想你跟我f你c我的事
I think you should tell me the story of you and my mom.
你槭颤N一直Q她椤肝」？ 好像我奈匆^她似的
Why do you keep saying "my mom" like I've never met her?
因槟阋x婚了
Well, because now that you're getting divorced,
所以她是我的，  不是你的
she's mine, not yours.
-是@幔 -告V我你的事
-Is that so? -Tell me how it happened.
真的故事，  不是什N 「我相遇K相
And the real story, not the, "Oh, we met, we fell in love,
「然後Q定用我的
"and we decided to take all that love
「建立一家庭K生下你」
"and make a family, and that's how we made you."
你知道幔课告V你 我跟你相R的
You know something? I'm gonna tell you the real, true story
睚去}
of how me and your mother met.
-等我L大r -]e
-When I'm old enough. -Yep.
-我知道矍椴皇峭 -真的？
-Look. I know love isn't a fairytale. -Really?
真的
Really.
你在JR她之前有e的女友幔
Did you have another girlfriend before you met her?
(CHUCKLES)
拜，  跟我f情
Come on, tell me the truth.
(SIGHS)
我有固定的女友
I had two serious girlfriends.
有一些在交往的女人
And then some other, a smattering of other women that I dated.
你知道
You know.
什N？
What?
男生的D叫什N？
What's the boy word for slut?
他]有想到那名~ 但我相信他正在想
They still haven't come up with one yet, but I'm sure they're working on it.
你@Y拜吃素幔
You a vegetarian this week or not?
-嗯，  吃素 -好
-Yeah, I am. -Great.
我猜你也不是她的初
I'm guessing you weren't her first boyfriend.
他可能是y子或是很
Maybe it was some nerdy guy, or maybe he was mean.
或S
Or maybe
(FAUCET RUNNING)
你了很久的朋友
you were friends for the longest time,
然後正你⒛愕纳殖器
and then just when you were about to put your penis
放M另一女人的道r…
into somebody else』s vagina...
晚安，雅
Okay. Good night, Maya.
…你lF才是你的至郏
...you realized Mom was the only one for you!
睡Xrg！
Bedtime!
你是得告V我你楹凵纤
You still have to tell me the story of why you fell in love with her.
我凵纤是因樗很明 漂亮又好玩
I fell in love with her because she was smart and beautiful and fun.
那她F在就又蠢又h又o聊了幔
So now she's stupid and ugly and boring?
-然不 -那}出在哪？
-Of course not. -Then what's the problem?
-很}s，雅 -你什N都很}s
-It's complicated, Maya. -Everything with you is so complicated.
我想若是你跟我f了那故事 你就不X得一切都如此}s了
I bet that if you just told me the story, you'd realize that it's not complicated at all.
你就是鬯
That you just love her.
我知道@事δ碚f很Dy 但你在想什N？
I know this is tough for you, but what are you thinking?
你J楣适抡f完後就]事了幔
That I'm gonna tell you this story and it's gonna make everything better?
人生]那N
It doesn't work that way.
也S是，  也S不 跟我v了後我就知道了
Maybe it does, maybe it doesn't. Tell me and we'll find out.
不，  玩完了，  睡X了
No. Game over. It's time for bed.
不，  不是睡X的r候 是你跟我f那故事的r候
No, it's not time for bed! It's time for you to tell me the story!
-雅 -我需要知道！
-Maya. -I need to know!
我需要知道
I need to know.
好啦！好啦！
Fine! Fine!
我跟你f
I'm gonna tell you the story,
-但不告V你哪是你 -好
-but I'm not telling you who your mom is. -Fine.
你得自己弄清楚
You're just gonna have to figure it out for yourself.
-好 -我用化名
-Good. -And I'm changing all the names
K更Q一些 不^@是我F在才想到的
and some of the facts, but I just decided that right now.
-然後我再砜纯茨阌卸嗦明 -我喜g，  像是矍榧乙晒适
-And then we'll see how smart you are. -I like it. It's like a love story/mystery.
-很好，  聿诲e，  浜昧幔 -]
-Great. Sounds good. You ready? -No.
]
No.
-慢慢 -我的
-Take your time. -I will.
-我知道你 -你磉@Y
-I know you will. -You go here.
-公主枕^？ -xx
-Princess pillow? -Thank you.
-]} -好
-You bet. -Okay.
(SIGHS)
我好了
I'm ready.
很久很久以前
Once upon a time,
在]有]、手Cc真人秀之前
before e-mails and cell phones and reality television shows,
美青年民主hT
_切碚f是1992年 在威斯康辛州的一叫迪d的小
in 1992 to be exact, in a little town called Madison, Wisconsin,
住了位名叫威廉海s的青年
there lived a young man named William Hayes.
-嘿，  威，老兄，  新年快 -嘿，  你也是
-Hey, Will, man, Happy New Year. -Hey, yeah, you, too.
@名青年深壑他在大W的女友
Now, this young man was deeply, deeply in love with his college sweetheart.
就叫她…
Let's call her...
-艾蜜莉！ -艾蜜莉！
-Emily! -Emily!
艾蜜莉！
Emily!
-嘿 -嗨
-Hey. -Hi.
10、9、8…
ALL: Ten, nine, eight...
嘿，猜猜再^4秒後 l是全世界最幸福的人？
Hey, guess who's gonna be the luckiest guy on planet Earth in about four seconds?
你
You.
…2、1！
ALL: ...two, one!
新年快罚
Happy New Year!
他是金童玉女
They were a perfect couple.
除了要真正t解@青年
Except to really understand how this young man
最後楹稳⒘四隳赣H 你必要先知道
ended up marrying your mother, you'll also need to know
他驯е一又大 又令人y榍榈粝
that he had a very big, incredibly embarrassing dream.
起立
All rise
向美y致敬
for the President of the United States of America,
威廉
William
R修
Matthew
海s
Hayes.
你想y幔
(CHUCKLING) You wanted to be President?
我只是，  我不懂你楹我在~s 涂铝诸D做事
I'm just, I don't understand why you have to work for Clinton in New York.
你楹尾荒茉邴迪d替他u命呢？
Why can't you just work for him in Madison?
因檫@不需要人，  他需要我去~s
Well, because they don't need me here. They need me in New York.
他需要他，  小艾，  威太帕 我不敢相信你要他去
They need him, Em. Will's the man. I can't believe you're letting him go.
你]f^~s的女孩子幔
I mean, don't you know about New York girls?
除了L相超辣之外 她完全不介意一夜情
Besides being incredibly hot, they have no problem with casual sex,
我可是非常同
which by the way, I totally respect.
-f一o查理f中了呢？ -查理]f^
-What if Charlie』s right? -Charlie』s never right.
-他是智障 -我很心~s改你
-He's functionally retarded. -I am worried New York's gonna change you.
-改也可能是好的 -如果我一起改
-Change can be good. -If we change together.
那我就一起改啊
So, we'll change together.
好幔坎贿^就去~s月 我一下就回砹
Okay? It's two months in New York. I'll be back before you know it.
r且，  我有，  幔
Besides, we have a plan, right?
另一件事是我不敢相信 你竟然敢把艾蜜莉跟我留在@
The other thing I can't believe is that you'd risk Ieaving Emily here with me,
我得f，  我δ阋恢庇泻酶小
'cause I gotta tell you, I've always had a thing for you...
r且我完全]有道德可言
And I have absolutely no scruples.
等等！我差c忘了 你要把@o夏曼
Wait! I almost forgot. You have to give this to Summer.
她是我在~s唯一JR的女生
She's the only girl I know in New York.
-我希望你她 -夏曼哈德尼？
-I want you to meet her. -Summer Hartley?
- -她的名字？
-Yes. Yes. -That's her name?
她是我在虍交QW生rJR的
She was on my exchange program at Cambridge,
所有的男生都想跟她上床 你看到她r或S也@N想吧
and all the guys wanted to sleep with her, and you probably will, too.
或S你寄o她
Maybe you should mail it to her.
-可能好些 -不
-That might be a better idea. -No.
是什N？
What is it?
一游液芫靡郧熬驮o她的|西
Something I should have sent her a long time ago.
我勰悖  威廉海s
I love you, William Hayes.
(CAR HORN HONKING)
好吧，  快走、快走，  好好做
Okay. Go, go, go. Go be your brilliant self.
艾蜜莉硐袷好
Emily sounds like she would make a good mom.
-我只是不_定她是不是我 -槭颤N？
-I just don't know if she's my mom. - Why not?
大家都知道
Everyone knows that the girlfriend
在故事最初的女朋友一定被甩
in the beginning of the story always gets dumped.
@表示夏曼哈德尼可能是我
Which means maybe Summer Hartley is my mother.
我永h忘不了那天
I'll never forget that day.
我淼搅裘乱郧蟮某鞘
There I was, arriving in the city I always dreamed about
槲疑钚诺母x活颖M一份力
to work on a campaign that I believed in with all of my heart.
更何r，  我深信在小r後
And on top of that, I was positive that in just a few hours,
活拥呢人就lF 我有多N的秀
the campaign manager would realize how brilliant I was.
然後我⒇v稿
And then I'd be writing speeches,
然後研l鹇裕  不久後…
and then I'd be coming up with strategy, and before long...
威海s？
GARETH: Will Hayes?
-嘿，  w瑞斯亨德d -你是w瑞斯
-Hey. Gareth Henderson. -You're Gareth.
-你好幔 -幸，  我走吧，  海s
-Hey, how are you? -Nice to meet you. We're walking, Hayes.
我Я宋业穆v表有一些 我褪吠尼hT的演v
I brought my C.V. and a sample of some speeches I wrote for Congressman Sweeney.
很好，  我在空nr 一定好好拜x一番
Fantastic. I cannot wait to peruse these in my abundant spare time.
在那之前，  @些咖啡c培果
In the meantime, here's a sample of the coffee and bagel order
需要aR
I'll need filled immediately.
等等！
Wait!
你要我去I咖啡？
You want me to get coffee?
每人都有某r期要I咖啡 F在到你了，  快c
At some point in our lives, we all get coffee. Your time's now. Come on.
海s，  我在走
We're still walking, Hayes.
咖啡早上十c要到 不然瑟⒘宋遥
Have the coffee here by 10:00, or Arthur's gonna kill me!
就表示我就得⒘四 我以前可是下^手，  海s
That means I'm gonna have to kill you. I've killed before, Hayes.
-你要知道 -@是什N？
-You should know that. -What is this?
@是手C
That is a cellular telephone
我可SrS地榱巳魏问抡业侥
so I can get a hold of you wherever, whenever, for whatever.
-l臀夷眯┌⑺蛊レ`好幔 -小心c！
-Can somebody get me an aspirin, please? -Watch it!
g迎你加入，  海s！
Glad to have you aboard, Hayes!
-嗨 -什N？嗨
-Hi. -What? Hi.
4周後，  ~s的x民
ARTHUR: Four weeks from now, voters of New York State
⑦x出下一玫拿裰鼽hy候x人
will select their next Democratic nominee for President.
若比柯林DA了
Now, if Bill Clinton wins,
我要你知道那⑹
I want you to all understand that it's gonna be as a direct result
在座每一人的心血所a生的Y果
of the commitment and the energy of every person in this room.
我是f真的，  那是事
And I mean that. That's just a fact.
@工作就是如此重要
Now, that's how important the work is.
在座的每一位…
That each and every one of you is...
(WILLIAM SCREAMS)
(CRASHING)
我在@做什N？
(SHOUTING) What am I doing here?
新淼
It's the new guy.
-嘿 -嘿，  那是送l生的人幔
-Hey. -Hey, is that the toilet paper guy?
-可以o我一包摩利t幔 -三K擅五
-Can I get a pack of Morley Red, please? -3.25.
三K擅五？ 在威州迪d才uK一毛五
3.25? These are $2.15 in Madison, Wisconsin.
那你就回迪d啊
So go back to Madison.
-得信 -]e，  得要信
-Don't forget to write. -That's right. Don't forget to write.
等等！停止！
Hold it! Stop. Stop right there!
你曾抽？
You smoked?
不，  是啦
No. Yeah.
但我本聿淮蛩愀你f的
But I didn't mean to tell you that.
著，  我那r很年pK很蠢 我很多年]抽了
Listen. I was young, and I was stupid, and I haven't smoked in years.
我l誓
I promise you.
有什N跟我f的？
Is there anything else you should tell me?
大概]有吧
Probably not.
-能臀矣坝∈份幔 -跟那B放在一起
-Can I get 10 copies? -Put them on the pile.
不，  是瑟要的 我15分前就拿到了
No, they're for Arthur. I need them like, 15 minutes ago.
你若不介意的…
So if you wouldn』t mind...
你是送l生的那砘
You're the toilet paper guy.
-慢著，  那是l？ -那是艾波
Wait. Who's that?  That's April.
]e，  我正是送l生的那砘
Yes. I am, in fact, the toilet paper guy,
但你也可Q我樗团喙c咖啡的砘
but feel free to call me the bagel-and-coffee guy.
部的陶德叫我克莉z朵 我很_信那是女生的名字
Or Todd in Accounting calls me Crystal, which I'm pretty sure is a girl』s name.
-追荩 -印十份
-How many copies? -Ten. Please.
-@些？ -Γ  擅娑家
-These? -Yeah, both of those.
你槭颤N支持柯林D？
What made you become a Bill Clinton supporter?
我]有啊，  我是支薪的，  一小r12K
I'm not. This is a money gig. I get paid 12 an hour,
比看小孩好多了 我褓母已到了
which is better than babysitting, which is what I've been doing way too much of.
你是民主hT幔
You're a Democrat, right?
人槭颤N非得是 民主h或共和hT才行呢？
Why does everyone have to be a Democrat or a Republican?
我B影印C都搞不定
I'm struggling with the copy machine.
等等，  你是立h的？
No, hold on. You're an Independent, aren't you?
我什N都不是 我槭颤N一定要跟哪h派？
I am nothing. Why am I obligated to be something?
我槭颤N要γ考事都有立觯
Why do I have to have an opinion about everything anyway?
f真的，  我w系y
I mean, really, what do I know about missile systems
或社安全或法又t解多少？
or Social Security, or the tax code?
那民嗯c女嗄兀
What about civil rights or women's rights?
女人胎的嗔δ兀窟@件事呢？
A woman's right to do what she wants with her body? What about that?
我主我的身w
I do what I want with my body.
那犹冷漠了
That's apathetic.
-我才不冷漠 -你是
-I'm not apathetic. -Yes, you are.
我]有，  我只知道 你在u命的那群蠢蛋
I'm not. I just know that these bozos you're working for,
除了他自己的野心之外 什N都不在乎
they don't care about anything more than their own ambitions.
才不是那
That's absolutely not true.
你真的X得比柯林D@砘 能做什N大改幔
You think this guy, Bill Clinton, is gonna make a huge difference?
-我相信 -他⒆龅亩际o可避免的
-I do. -He's gonna do what's already inevitable.
-你e就e在@ -e逼我用C你的^！
-Okay, that's where you're wrong. -Don't make me staple your head!
你e了，  他⒏纳坪谌嘁
You're wrong. He's gonna make a difference with African Americans.
也⒏纳D女嘁妫  他t解女性
He's gonna make a difference with women. He gets women.
-天啊 -我是f，  看看他在阿肯色的政E
-My God. -I mean, look at his record in Arkansas.
去x一下他的保健 去x一下他的教育
Read his plans on health care. Read his plans on education.
-好吧，  ex，  嗯 -天啊，  真抱歉
-Okay, or don't. You know, yeah. -Oh, my God, I'm sorry.
-嗯，抱歉 -我睡著了
-Yeah, I'm sorry. -I just fell asleep.
-很抱歉 -]PS
-I'm really sorry. -Yeah. That's fine.
醒r就是新美了
Wake up to a new America.
-我相信你 -@次交真有趣
-I believe you. -This has been really interesting.
-很好，  你f服了我，  你是oh籍 -我oh籍
-Fine. You convinced me. You're nothing. -I'm nothing.
我在T位前再度重申…
FLOWERS ON TV: So I'm here to repeat in front of all of you...
嘿！著！大家快看！
Hey! Listen up! Look up, everybody!
珍妮佛芙斯 Q柯林D情D
是的，  我了 比柯林D的情D超_12年
Yes, I was Bill Clinton's lover for 12 years.
嘿，  l_大c
Hey, somebody turn it up.
^去的赡曛校  我榱吮Ｗo他 而γ襟w[m我z的PS
For the past two years, I have lied to the press about our relationship to protect him.
事上，  我圻^他
The truth is, I loved him.
(PEOPLE EXCLAIMING)
但他F在要我否J
Now he tells me to deny it.
我倦了@所有的欺mce言
Well, I'm sick of all of the deceit, and I'm sick of all of the lies.
你倒是fα艘稽c 他的_很t解女人
Well, you're right about one thing. He certainly gets women.
-@次很有趣 -再，l生砘
-This has been fun. Yeah. -(LAUGHING) Bye, toilet paper guy.
再，  影印小妹
Bye, copy girl.
天啊，  真]完]了
Oh, my God. It never ends.
他就一直不停的重}播放
They just keep playing it over and over and over again.
-^去的 -是喔
- It's gonna bIow over. -Right.
人不在乎@N事情
PeopIe don't really care about this stuff.
-@是重c -我不懂的是
-That's the thing. -What I don't understand,
我f布希也有情D
I've heard Bush has a mistress.
大家都在 槭颤N他可以而柯林D就不行？
Everybody's talking about it, so why is it okay for him and not for Clinton?
她很S便
She's trashy.
光看到她的型 就足以用此砉艨铝诸D
I mean, her hair alone is enough reason to go after Clinton.
有什N大不了的 每人都有弱c，  了幔
Big deal. Everyone has their weaknesses, you know?
那些著假指甲，  肉肉的t女人？
Those chubby redheads with the long, fake fingernails?
-老子就喜g@N -好亨
-That's what Daddy likes. -That's just nasty.
w瑞斯，  你有蛴
Gareth, you are unfailingly repugnant.
嘿，  太巧了，  我最喜gf 「有蛴」的女人
Hey. That is a coincidence. I love women that say "unfailingly repugnant."
知道我喜g哪的幔
You know what I love?
我喜g棕色L K戴著粗框眼R的女人
I love long-haired brunettes with horn-rimmed glasses.
我也不知道槭颤N 她就像是我的死穴
I have no idea why. They're like kryptonite to me.
我也是
I got that one, too.
我抗拒不了被我吸引的男人
I got a thing for guys who've got a thing for me.
你或S看看心理t生，  我要e杯
You might wanna look at that. I'm gonna propose a toast.
]}
I am fine with that.
-敬比c他的弱c -
-To Bill and his weaknesses. -Yes.
-敬比 -敬比
-To Bill. -To Bill.
(HIP HOP MUSIC PLAYING)
(PHONE RINGING)
喂？
Hello?
嘿！是我！
Hey! It's me!
-是艾蜜莉幔 -是艾蜜莉幔
-Is that Emily? -Is that Emily?
-嗨，  艾蜜莉！ -嗨，  艾蜜莉！
-Hi, Emily! -Hi, Emily!
怎N那N吵？
What's all that noise?
]什N，  我的白V同事在取笑我
Nothing. That's just a couple of idiots I work with making fun of me
因樗]有一生至鄣钠亮女友
because they don't have a beautiful girlfriend that they're eternally devoted to!
你喝醉了
You're drunk.
你好美
You're beautiful.
-你l情了 -可能被你f中了
-You're horny. -You might be right.
(EMILY LAUGHING)
艾蜜莉？到~s
Emily? Come to New York.
你很喜g的 @Y的活力c人群真的很棒
You'll love it here. It's the energy, the people. It's amazing.
等等，  你f「活力」幔 威，  你]f「活力」吧？
Whoa, did you just say "energy"? Will, you did not just say "energy."
什N？
What?
你不回砹
You're never coming back.
嘿，  拜 我只是想要你^矶纫L末
Hey, come on, now. I just want you to come for a weekend.
你f得Γ抱歉
You're right. I'm sorry.
你有j到夏曼幔
Did you call Summer?
]有，  我留了言，  她]有回我
No. I left her a message. She didn't get back to me.
嘿，  你好幔
Hey. You okay?
嗯，  只是很寂寞
Yeah. I'm just really lonely here,
我想死你了，  真的很y熬
and I miss you like crazy, and it's really hard.
嗯，  我懂你的意思
Yeah. I know what you mean.
-你怎N]睡？ -克~先生
-Hey. What are you doing up? - Mr. McCormack.
拜，  你已盯著那包裹一Y拜了
Come on, you've been staring at that package for about a week now.
你今晚怎N樱靠砗艹晒
How was the rest of your evening? Successful, I take it.
老天，  我K了，  我凵线@女孩了！
Oh, my goodness. I'm in big trouble. I love this girl!
那通常是件好事
You know, that's usually a good thing.
要第一位黑人y就已蚶щy了
It's hard enough to get elected the first black President
真的不需要在就典Yr е茱莉_勃
without having Julia Roberts on your arm at the inauguration.
你的想像力真S富，  小_
That is an impressive mental leap, Russ,
囊灰骨樘到y宣誓
going from a one-night stand to being sworn in as President.
打_它
Open it.
我知道你很想知道Y面是什N
I know you're dying to know what's inside.
光是她的名字，  夏曼哈德尼 就我快…
Just her name alone, Summer Hartley, is driving me...
你看！@破掉了！我看到了
Look it! You got a tear right there! I see it.
快c，  你可以的
Come on through. You can do it.
xx你，
Thank you. Yes.
-是本日 -老天，  我看看
-It's a diary. -Sweet Jesus. Let me see.
不！住手，  我不能x@本日
No! Stop! Stop right there. We're not gonna read this. We can't.
「男子宿舍在γ 窗口正χ我的窗
"The boys' dorm is across the quad, their windows visible from ours.
「晚上又嵊逐
"The evenings are hot and sticky.
「我都衣衫不整的 假bγ娴哪猩看不到我
"We are all half-dressed, pretending we can't be seen by the boys.
「有些女孩很大，  我的新朋友
"Some of us are bold. My new friend
「艾蜜莉人很好
"Emily is sweet
「K@一切感到y榍 她永h都在等我下一步怎N做」
"and embarrassed by it all, always waiting to see what I will do."
e停啊！@很疟，  你念到哪？好
Don't stop! This is good stuff. Where were you? Okay.
「@是我的最後一晚 已了好滋
"It's our last night, and the plan has been in place for days.
「艾蜜莉c我是最後x_的
"Emily and I are the last to leave,
「我走到翘菘r 我抓住了艾蜜莉的手腕
"and as we reach the stairs, I grab Emily firmly by her wrist.
「她抬^以期盼的眼光看著我 我知道接下l生什N事」
"She looks up at me expectantly and I know what will happen next."
-你知道幔 -我想我知道吧
-Do you? -I think I have a pretty good idea.
我的天！
Oh, my goodness!
你在致铮窟@可是好料的，老兄！
What are you doing? This is good stuff, man!
等等
Wait a minute.
是你的艾蜜莉幔
Is that your Emily?
晚安，  _素！
Good night, Russell!
她好狂野！
She is a freak!
把照片放回去！
Put the picture back!
W
Wow.
-l啊？ -我是威海s，  之前打^
-HAMPTON: Who is it? -Will Hayes. I called earlier.
(CLEARS THROAT)
你是耶和AC的？
HAMPTON: You a Jehovah's Witness?
不
No.
老天，  你好高
Christ, you're tall.
(LATCH UNLOCKING)
嘿
Hi.
(BLUES MUSIC PLAYING ON PHONOGRAPH)
-M -好
-Come in. -Okay.
把TP上
CIose the door behind you.
i起恚
HAMPTON: Lock it!
夏曼要你等等 她回恚要你等一下
Summer said to hang tight. She'll be back. She wants you to wait.
-你手上拿著什N？ -不知道，  你是夏曼的父H幔
-What do you got in there? -I don't know. Are you Summer's father?
Γ  我是她的老子
Yeah. I'm her daddy.
-喝酒幔 -不，  有c太早了
-Drink? -No. No. It's a little early for me.
早，  你才聿痪茫  是幔
Early. You're fresh off the boat, aren't you?
你自己吧，F在怎N樱 有什N理想？
So tell me about yourself. What's your deal? What do you aspire to?
有什N粝幔磕阆g些什N？
What are your dreams? What are your fancies?
L大後想要做什N？
What do you want to be when you grow up?
-坐下！ -好
-Sit down! -Okay.
你在哪Y高就？你…
What do you do now? You...
等等，  我猜，  你湍惆肿鍪
Wait, don't tell me. You work for your daddy.
-不 -不，  e跟我f！
-No. -No, don't tell me!
A街，  不！
Wall Street. No!
你在上城某家大律所拍R屁
You kiss ass to some fancy uptown law firm.
-其… -不！我放，  你是做什N的？
-Actually... -No! I give up. What do you do?
我捅柯林D做事，  他在xy
I'm working for Bill Clinton. He's running for President.
不是吧
No.
我知道比柯林D是l
I know who Bill Clinton is.
事上，  我比比柯林D他 要t解他
Yeah, in fact, I know more about Bill Clinton than his own mother.
-真的？ -嗯
-Really? -Yep.
-你在哪高就？ -我在哪高就？
-What do you do? -What do I do?
我喝酒！
I drink!
喝！
Drink!
男人
Be a man.
就是@樱『枚嗔税桑
There you go! Isn』t that better?
吞下它！
Swallow!
跟我比柯林D
So tell me about Bill Clinton.
嘿，  醒醒
Hey. Wake up.
你要阿斯匹`幔
You want some aspirin?
-你一定是威 -嗨
-You must be Will. -Hi.
看砟愎嘧砹宋夷信笥
I see you drank my boyfriend under the table.
-他不是你爸？ -他@痈你f的幔
- He's not your father? -(CHUCKLES) Is that what he told you?
Hmm.
他是我的文指
He's my thesis advisor.
Oh.
他f了什N？
What else did he tell you?
他教我如何做一真男人，  而不是
He was telling me how to be a real man, as opposed to the sort of
-像我F在@小毛^ -你W到了什N？
-boy-man I seem to be. -Did you learn anything?
嗯，要喝很多酒
Yeah, there's a lot of drinking involved.
有Rvc旨
AIso cursing and fighting.
-性？ -
-Sex? -Yes.
不^我真男人不用那字眼
Although that's not what we real men call it.
那你怎Nf？
What do you call it?
我有|西要o你 是艾蜜莉要我D交的
I have something for you. This is from Emily.
-我好久]跟她j了 -我今年秋天就要同居
-Haven't talked to her in ages. -We'll be moving in together in the fall.
Uh-huh.
拜！老爸
Oh, please! Daddy.
(LAUGHING)
拜！不
Oh, come on! No.
@是…
Oh, this is...
她等待著我的回而我屈服了 我吻了她
你看^了幔
Did you read this?
]有
I didn't.
-我看了一 -一
-I read a page. -A page.
-最多身 -身？
-Two pages at the most. -Two?
你c艾蜜莉接吻c互岬哪嵌
And the part about you and Emily touching each other and kissing.
-那段，  嗯 -很@的描述，  像是身入其境
-Oh! That part, yeah. -Incredibly descriptive. I felt like I was there.
你的文P很好，  我是f…
You're a great writer. I mean...
我想@o你，  你寂寞r可以看看
I think you should keep it. You should read it when you're lonely.
-我不能，  是你的日，  我不能留著 -不，  真的，  我不需要它
-I can't. It's your diary, so I can't do that. -No, really, really. I just, I don't need it.
我已背起砹耍  我就留在桌上
I've already got it memorized, so I'll just leave it on the table.
原版的你就留著吧 @ξ碚f比^好
Keep a hard copy. That might be nice for me.
(BOTH LAUGHING)
我很好奇艾蜜莉楹我你斫o我
I wonder why Emily gave it to you to give to me.
Hmm.
h普D？
Hampton?
-h普D？ -你要加入我幔
-Hampton? -Are you gonna join us?
他是h普D_斯，  知名作家
That's Hampton Roth. He's an incredible writer.
-他那本P於高文x活拥… -是啊
-His book on the McGovern campaign is... -Yeah.
-你… -是啊，  我做了
-You... -Yeah. We do.
著，  你有跟年^六十的人 上床^幔
Look, have you ever actually had sex with a sexagenarian?
-我]有 -那你就不批判
-I haven't. -Well, then you shouldn't really judge.
我]有在批判，  你看你
Well, actually, I'm not judging. Look at you.
你很美、很世故 又是很有才A的作家
You're beautiful. You're sophisticated. You're a very talented writer.
xx
Thank you.
能M足你@拥呐人的人一定是…
I mean, to please a woman like you, it would obviously take a...
-真男人 -正是
-Real man. -Exactly.
-很y成樗的κ -除非你是心很的那N人
-Hard to compete with that. -Well, unless you're the competitive type.
-嗯，  幸 -嗯，  也很高dJR你
-Yep, nice to meet you. -Yeah, it was great meeting you, too.
我真的很抱歉拿了…
I feel horrible about taking the...
抱歉
Sorry.
我只是好奇
I was just curious.
h普D鼓钗胰グl掘我的好奇心
Hampton encourages me to cultivate my curiosity.
他f@Τ橐幻好者非常重要
He says it's the key to being a good journalist.
是啊
Yeah.
夏曼！老子I了！
HAMPTON: Summer! Daddy's hungry!
f曹操，  曹操到，  我得M去了
-Speak of the devil. Better go. Yeah. -Hmm.
你他的在哪？
HAMPTON: Where the hell are you?
-好，  再 -再
-Okay, bye. -Bye.
嗯，  有空打 我可以一起出去吃晚餐
Yeah, give us a call sometime. We should all go out for dinner.
我…好啊，  晚餐聿诲e
I'd... Yeah, I'd love dinner.
-嗯 -嘿！
-Yeah. -HAMPTON: Hey!
-你要打o她幔 -你了幔
-Are you gonna call her? -Are you insane?
-你要怎N做呢？ -我要怎N做？
-Well, what are you gonna do? -What am I gonna do?
(DANCE MUSIC PLAYING)
我要Ｗ⒃谀松 艾蜜莉c我是有未淼模  我有
I'm gonna keep my eye on the ball. Emily and I have a future. We have a plan.
F在可能包括3P
Which may involve some type of threesome now.
若那老砘镞在的就是4P了
Or foursome if that old dude is still in the picture.
你@是在偷姑
You're not helping.
我根本不打_那本日的 它就像是潘朵拉又辣又性感的箱子
I never should have opened that diary. It's like Pandora's hot, sexy box.
3P是什N？
What's a threesome?
-什N？ -3P
-What? A threesome.
那是大人o聊r玩的[
That's a game that adults play sometimes when they're bored.
S便啦，  那艾蜜莉怎N恿耍
Whatever. So what happened with Emily?
]怎樱  我想等到她砜次
Nothing. I wanted to wait till she came for a visit,
然後我Q定做一件很⌒缘氖
and then I decided to do something really dramatic.
那rx初x只剩下一周了
It was just one week before the primary, and I had graduated
我也呐喙cl生 升到迅媾c汽帖
from bagels and toilet paper to signs and bumper stickers.
(SCREAMS)
老天！
Jesus! Mercy!
稍等
Hold, please.
我在@质颤N？
What am I doing here?
^去！再^去一尺！再一尺，  ^去！
Move over! Another foot! Go, another foot. Move over!
^去、^去、^去！
Over, over, over!
我只想大家知道新的迅浜昧
Just want to let everyone know that the new signs are ready.
看砗馨
They're looking good.
我褪吠尼hT^三次演v稿
I wrote three speeches for Congressman Sweeney.
(STAPLING CONTINUES)
高中上的怎樱
How's high school?
他是德州人，  名叫讨尾枷 但他不是y
He's from Texas. His name's George Bush. But he is not the President.
他是讨闻c芭芭拉的L子
Instead, he's the eldest son of George and Barbara
也是白m鹊⒅\之一
and considered a key political advisor of the White House.
布R特，  你忘了提德州巡
Bryant, well, you forgot to mention the Texas Rangers.
喔，  是的
BRYANT: Oh, okay.
@砘镆是蚵明，  就回去打棒球
Man, if this guy's smart, he'll go back to baseball.
-真的 -有人看到海s幔
-No kidding. -Anybody see Hayes?
-] -]
-No. -No.
海s！海s呢？海s！
Hayes! Where is Hayes? Hayes!
你是你迪dI的高材生 是真的幔
Is it true you graduated first of your class at Madison?
-嗯 -好吧
-Yeah. -All right.
-^恚  我去散步 -我去散步
-Come on. We're walking. -We're walking.
@是目前居住在~s的迪d校友
Here's a list of Madison graduates in the New York area.
@些人的年收入都超^20f
These people earn 200 grand plus a year.
我星期一的募款晚宴剩15席 一fK一人^的位子
We have a $10,000-a-plate fundraiser on Monday with 15 empty tables.
@可不行，  海s 我需要你推N五席出去
I can't have that, Hayes. I need you to sell five of them.
等等，  不用I咖啡c培果了？
Hold on. No more coffee, bagels?
-那得看你@次表F如何，  好幔 -w瑞斯
-We'll see how this goes, okay? -Gareth.
-什N？ -xx，  我F在很高d
-What? -Thank you. I'm really happy right now.
-好的，  海s -好的
-Okay, Hayes. -Okay.
-桌子在那 -你看看，  好
-There's the desk. -Look at that. Yeah.
嗯，很好笑，l生
Yeah, that's funny, the toilet paper.
很S刺，很棒
That's good because it's ironic.
]e，  大家，  我的桌子
Yeah, that's right, everybody. My desk.
就在@，  我有桌子，  有名
Right here, I got a desk, and I got a list.
我有c@空@子
And I have a phone. And this empty basket.
不、不、不，  我不J
No, no, no, I really don't agree
州L的人格有}，  波曼太太
that the Governor has a character problem, Mrs. Perleman.
您知道全美有50%的人J
Did you know that 50% of Americans believe that
大麻合法化幔
marijuana use should be legalized?
(PHONE LINE DRONES)
喂？
Hello?
不、不、不，  他K未逃避徵兵
No, no, no, he wasn't a draft dodger.
r且，  您知道大多档拿人都J
Besides, did you know that the majority of Americans believe
越鹗很糟的c子幔
that the Vietnam War was just a terrible idea?
l腿
Both legs.
W，抱歉，  您一定很想念它
Wow, I am sorry. You must miss them.
(PHONE LINE DRONES)
是，  我t解你的] 但我想您要得
Yes, I understand your concern, but I think you should remember
州L的家l是名橄Ｍ的小
that the Governor comes from a town called Hope.
他也象徵著希望，  所以…
And hope is exactly what he stands for, so...
不、不，  我知道那很土，  但我也J
No, no, I know it's corny, but I also think
有r@家所需的正是一c土
that sometimes corny is exactly what this country needs.
那太好了，  不，  xx您
That would be wonderful. No, thank you.
位子
Two seats.
好的，  xx您，  雪先生
Okay, great. Thank you, Mr. Bishop.
是的，  餐在下星期四
Yeah, the dinner's next Thursday.
是的，  我今早c希拉蕊通^
Yes, when I spoke with Hillary this morning
她f她想要更深入JR 我最重要的支持者
she said that she wanted to get to know our most important supporters.
不，  我相信您很高dJR她的
No, I think you'd definitely enjoy meeting her.
嗯
Yeah.
一整桌？不，  那^τ锌赡
An entire table? No, that is very possible.
我就湍下一桌_，  太好了
I'll put you down for one table, then. That sounds great.
好的，  我很期待下星期四c您面
Okay, I look forward to seeing you next Thursday.
好的，  xx
Okay, thank you.
我u了一整桌5f
I just sold an entire table for $50,000.
(ALL CHEERING)
那是我的人，  威，  我的人
That's my guy, Will. My guy.
l生砘铮⌒l生砘铮
ALL: (CHANTING) Toilet paper guy! Toilet paper guy!
先生，  晚安，  o我一包摩立t
Good evening, gentlemen. Pack of Reds, please.
三K六毛，  多了新c警示
3.60. New tax and a new warning.
老天
Christ.
警告：  吸е侣LK痛苦的死亡
f吧，  朋友
Tell us the truth, my friend.
-柯林D到底有]有拉麻？ -有差幔
-Did that Clinton inhale or not? -What does it matter?
那就像是你女朋友抓到你 c另一女人在床上，  然後你f
That's like if your girlfriend catches you in bed with another woman, then you say,
「可是我]做」
"But we didn't do it."
-λ碚f有差幔 -有差啊，  嗨
-What, is that gonna matter to her? -Yeah, it does. Hi.
-哈_ -o我一包美{
-Hello. -Pack of American Eagles, blue, please.
四K擅五
4.25.
四K擅五？ 你花四K擅五I一包？
4.25? You pay $4.25 for a pack of cigarettes?
Y面的化W物品比^少
They don't put as many chemicals in them.
-所以是健康的香_ -算是吧
-So those are healthy cigarettes. -Something like that.
若]有那N多的化W品
So if there's not as many chemicals in them,
你不X得要比^便宜才幔
they should cost less, not more, don't you think?
你的YB有硝酸
They put saltpeter in your cigarettes,
它得比^快，  也你抽更多
which make them burn faster, which make you smoke more.
意思就是，  你的其比^F
Which means, at the end of the day, your cigarettes actually cost more, not less.
影印小妹，  我X得你I的
Copy girl, what I think you're actually paying for
是一有漂亮粉色系老的D像
is the picture of the eagle and the pretty pastel colors.
一你ι活方式放心的f~ 其N的都是狗屎
Some reassuring idea about your lifestyle. The rest is pretty much crap.
-要幔 -好啊
-You wanna bet? -Sure.
-20元 -我有20元
-20 bucks. -I got 20 bucks.
最好的20元
Easiest 20 bucks I ever made.
-真的？ -嗯
-Really? -Yeah.
很有趣，  等我就有40元了
That's funny. In a minute, I'll have 40.
好，  我要同r吸入同拥姆萘
Okay, we have to inhale at the same time for the same amount of time.
- -A洌  _始
-Yep. -Ready, steady, go.
-今天是我生日 -生日快
-It's my birthday today. -Happy birthday.
怎N]出去c祝？
Why aren't you out celebrating?
我男友R卡斯本硪我去吃 然後去⒓优
My boyfriend, Lucas, was taking me out for dinner and then to a party.
但他Rr有工作要去M城 然，  他接下了@工作是因椤
But at last minute, he gets a gig in Philly, which, of course, he takes 'cause...
老f，  他Τ橄乱
Truth is he's far more interested in being
柯特寇本的d趣比我男友要大多了
the next Kurt Cobain than being my boyfriend.
柯特寇本是l？
Who's Kurt Cobain?
你在_玩笑吧？
You're kidding me!
什N？
What?
抽
Smoke.
Oh.
-你看 -你看
-Look at that. -Look at that.
(CLICKING TONGUE)
(GROANS)
(LAUGHING)
-好吧 -不，  e@
-All right. -No, come on.
光是知道我是Φ
The satisfaction of me being right
而你e了的M足感就足蛄
and you being wrong is more than enough for me.
我聿凰Ｙ的，  不如@影
Well, I never welsh on a bet, so I'll tell you what.
我你吃晚餐，  是生日晚餐
I'll take you out for dinner, for a birthday dinner.
-怎N樱 -像是s幔
-What do you say? -Like a date?
不，  我不是@意思
No, I didn't mean it like that.
像是「我可z你
Like an "I feel sorry for you
「^生日竟然]」的晚餐
"because it's your birthday and you have no plans" dinner.
-那N的 -嗯，  那@影
-You know, one of those. -Well, I'll tell you what.
你可以我去我原本要去的派
You can take me to this party I have to go to,
因槲铱]法为去面
because there's no way I can face going alone.
(TRIP HOP MUSIC PLAYING)
嗯，  我想我去…
Yeah, I'm gonna go head over...
Whoa.
我感X很突兀
I think I'm a little out of my league here.
你是啊
Yes, you are.
艾蜜莉是你的大W女友？
So Emily is what, like, your college sweetheart?
-你@N做法真的很害 -什N？
-It's amazing how you do that. -What?
你可以⒁痪浜芎蔚脑
The way you take the simplest statement,
扭曲成一很面的
and then you twist it with a completely negative connotation.
-真的很害，  我很佩服 -我不是那意思
-It's really, actually, impressive. I'm amazed. -I didn't mean to do that.
-但我懂，  我了 -我其X得那很感人
-But I understand. I get it. -I actually think it's very sweet.
-看，  你又砹 -真的？
-See, you did it again. -Really?
-嗯 -我自己都]察X
-Yeah. -I don't even know I'm doing it.
你或S很y想像 一基於互相尊重的偾
It's probably hard for you to imagine a relationship based on mutual respect
而不包括一zz你所^的被虐A向
without even the slightest hint of whatever you call it, masochism.
你c艾蜜莉的PS 若真像你f的那N完美
Well, if your deal with Emily is so gosh darn wonderful,
你槭颤N不娶她呢？
then why don't you just marry her?
什N阻止了你？
What's stopping you?
]有啊
Nothing.
-W -W
-Wow. -Wow.
她明天就收到了，  我了位
She gets it tomorrow. I made a reservation
在上|^一家很高n的法餐d
at some fancy French restaurant on the Upper East Side.
天啊，  你要在一群 不JR的人面前求婚？
Oh, my God. You're doing it in front of a room full of strangers?
-是啊，  有什N不妥幔 -]有，  @表示你很有自信
-Yeah, I am. What's wrong with that? -No, nothing. I think it shows confidence.
你要f什N？
What are you gonna say?
-我在想，  不知道 -你跟我
-I'm still working on it. I don't know. -Oh, you should work on it with me.
你跟我，  我在@方面很害 我硌莅蜜莉
You should practice with me. I'm really good at that. I will be Emily.
我是你的大W女友艾蜜莉 你有什N要我的幔
I'm Emily, your college sweetheart. Is there something you wanted to ask me?
-艾蜜莉… -等等！你要跪下
-Emily... -Wait! You've got to get down on your knee.
不，  我才不要跪下
No, I'm not getting down on my knee.
她喜g的，  她希望你跪下
She'll like it. She'll like seeing you down on your knee.
-我不要跪下 -那真是e大了，  好吧
-I'm not getting down on my knee. -Such a mistake. Okay.
-艾蜜莉 -是的，  威廉
-Emily. -Yes, William.
e惹我笑，  艾蜜莉
Don't make me laugh. Emily,
你意
will you,
um,
嫁o我幔
marry me?
-不 -我的天
-No. -Oh, my God.
什N叫做「你意嫁o我幔俊
Well, what do you mean, "Will you, um, marry me?"
我好Y拜]到你了！
I haven't seen you in weeks!
你ξ的婚姻前景 看硪稽c都不_心cd^！
You don't look happy or excited about the prospect of our marriage!
你要我放我的自由
You're asking me to give up my freedom,
我ono]的生活
my joie de vivre
榱艘成功c失÷半的制度？
for an institution that fails as often as it succeeds?
我槭颤N要嫁o你？ 你又槭颤N想要娶我呢？
And why should I marry you, anyway? I mean, why do you wanna marry me?
唯一理由就是能M足社 深植在我心中的理想中aAj望
Besides some bourgeois desire to fulfill an ideal that society embeds in us
c自小就灌在我心中的 消MY本主x
from an early age to promote a consumer capitalist agenda?
Oh!
我的天啊！
(CHUCKLING) Oh, my God!
-你要跪下的 -]嘴啦！
-You should've got on your knee! -Just shut up!
@
Here.
我想娶你，  是因槟闶俏乙辉缙
I wanna marry you because you're the first person
第一眼就想要到的人
that I want to look at when I wake up in the morning
K是我每晚睡前唯一想要吻的人
and the only one I wanna kiss goodnight.
因楫我第一次看到那p手r
Because the first time that I saw these hands,
我就o法想像不能恐它的日子
I couldn』t imagine not being abIe to hold them.
但最主要的，  你垡人 像我勰阋
But mainly, when you love someone as much as I love you
唯一剩下的就是Y婚
getting married is the only thing left to do.
所以你意…
So will you...
Um...
嫁o我幔
marry me?
^κ牵  或S
Definitely. Maybe.
我得考]一下
I have to think about it.
能送我回家幔
Walk me home?
(INDISTINCT CHATTERING)
-要不要喝杯茶？ -嗯，  好啊
-Do you want a cup of tea? -Yeah. I'd love one.
嘿
Hey.
你槭颤N有@N多版本的《邸罚
How come you have so many copies of Jane Eyre?
-f碓L -真的？
-It's a long story. -Really?
看上去好像只有三百多
It seems to be about 300 pages or so.
(LAUGHS)
f真的，  槭颤N？
Seriously, why?
我13q生日r，  想要一副金耳h
For my 13th birthday, I wanted a pair of gold stud earrings,
但我爸s臀屹I了精b版的《邸
and instead my dad bought me a hardcover copy of Jane Eyre.
Y^有他很美的}~ 但我r根本不在乎
And inside, he wrote a beautiful inscription, which I could care less about at the time
因槲疫在榱硕h的事生
seeing as I was so pissed about the earrings,
真的很z憾 因槟鞘撬o我最後的一份Y物
which was tragic as it turned out 'cause it was the last present he ever gave me.
什N意思？
What do you mean?
他在三周後因身亡
He died three weeks later in a car accident.
老天，  太K了
Jesus. That's awful.
我很抱歉
I'm sorry.
-你看^@本幔 -]有
-Have you ever read it? -No.
我每一、赡昃妥x一次 每次都不一
I read it every year or two. Each time it's different.
每次都得到不同的息
It tells me different things.
我去上大Wr，  我把房子u了
Anyhow, when I went away to college, my mom sold our house
在@之g，  那本《邸放G了
and somewhere along the way, Jane Eyre got lost.
F在我只要一^二手店
Now, every time I pass a second-hand bookstore,
就找我爸Io我的那本
I look for the copy that my dad bought me for my birthday.
(COME AS YOU ARE PLAYING)
我知道我找不到了
I know I'll never find it.
很蠢，  但@成了一怪又迷信的…
It's stupid, but it's become this, like, weird superstitious little...
-不蠢啦 -多x，  d趣
-It's not stupid. -Thanks. Hobby.
@些是什N？
What are all these?
@些是我找到Y面有}~的
Oh, these are the ones I found that have inscriptions.
「能有再次叟c希望c粝氲C 劾蚪z留」
"With love and hopes and dreams of second chances. Alice."
@是什N？
What is this?
@是柯特寇本，  @是超F 你喜g幔
This is Kurt Cobain. This is Nirvana. Do you like it?
我喜g
Yeah, I do.
你X得我想要 政治家很o稽，  幔
You think it's ridiculous that I want to be a politician, don't you?
- -xx你
-Yes. -Thank you.
不、不，  我t解想恼的理想 δ阌泻酶K不y
No, no, I get the whole politician thing. It's easy to like you.
那倒是真的，  的_
That's true. That's very true.
我很岩赡闶欠裣Ｍ 人家喜g你^了^
I just wonder if you want people to like you a little too much.
那倒也是
That's also true.
我要他我
I should want them to hate me.
我R上就_始朝那方向前M 你有什N忠告幔
I'm gonna start working on that right away. You got any tips for me?
不，  你已有好的_始
No, but you're off to a great start.
-是幔 -我已_始你了
-Yeah? -I'm hating you already.
很好
Good.
你L大後想要做什N？
What do you wanna be when you grow up?
我是f影印c小孩δ碚f
I mean, you're too smart to be making Xeroxes
-太浪M了 -不
-and babysitting. -No.
-我不知道！ -有一些有的]的
-I don't know! -Whatever else you do.
我不知道，  我也不知道 要怎硬拍苤道，  你知道幔
I don't know, and I don't know how to know. You know?
(SIGHS)
我真的想做的是
You know what I really wanna do
我想去些我完全不t解的地方
is I wanna go to all those places that I know nothing about.
我一直在存X
I've been saving money.
但我B@件事都搞不定
But I can't even get it together to do that.
或S是因槲易哌M了@砘锏乃篮同
Probably because I'm stuck in a rut with this guy.
你甩了他
You should dump him.
我知道@不P我的事，  但他配不上你
I know that's none of my business, but you're too good for him.
真的
You are.
-你知道酷的是什N幔 -不知道
-You know what's really cool? -I don't.
我z可以就坐在@Y，  不用去心
We can just sit here and we don't have to worry about
-{情c吸引力之的 -那些有的]的
-flirting or all the attraction stuff. All that stuff.
非常酷
Very cool.
嗯
Yeah.
(BLUES MUSIC PLAYING ON STEREO)
我得走了
I got to go.
白V！
Dumbass!
《~s客sI》
-天啊 -他回砹耍
-Oh, God. - There he is!
-就跟你f不很久 -嗨！我想o你@喜！
-Told you he wouldn』t be long. -Hi! I wanted to surprise you!
-我搭隔夜的班C淼模 -太棒了！
-I took the red-eye! -(WHEEZING) That's incredible!
我才在跟艾蜜莉f瑟 派你c先h伍去阿巴尼
I was just telling Emily how Arthur sent you to Albany as part of the advance team.
-先h伍 -Π。  怎N樱
Advance team. - Yeah. How'd it go?
-怎N樱坷闲郑利O了！ -很好
-How'd it go? Man, it went great! -Great.
-很好 -很好
-Great. -Great.
-你]事吧？ -]事，  我只是\右幌
-Are you okay? -Oh, yeah, I was just getting a little exercise.
-我跑上翘 -喔
-I ran up the stairs. -Okay.
我要去k公室，  @…明天很忙 很高dJR你
I'm going to the office. It's... Got a big day. Nice meeting you.
-你也是 -好
-And you. -Okay.
好
Okay.
祝你好\
(WHISPERING) Good luck.
-嗨 -嗨
-Hi. -Hi.
-@Y -嗯
-Here. -Yeah.
嘿
Hey.
-很怪，  你的舌^味道不一 -什N？
-It's weird. Your tongue tastes different. -What?
你的舌^味道不一
It tastes different, your tongue.
-真奇怪 -不模  就是不一
-That is weird. -It's not bad. It's just different.
或S是@Y的自硭吧
Maybe it's the tap water here.
再不然就是酸A平衡… 我不知道自己在胡言yZ些什N
Or the pH balance... I don't know what I'm talking about.
就跟你f~s改你
Told you New York was gonna change you.
-我可以去散步幔 -嗯
-Could we maybe go for a walk? -Yeah.
-去透透夂幔 -嗯，  你可以⒂^一下~s
-Just to get some air? -Yeah, you could see New York.
好啊
I would love that.
-我有跟你f… -我本怼
So, did I ever tell you...  I was gonna...
-抱歉，  不，  你f -什N？
-Oh, sorry. No, go. -What?
我才在f，  我有跟你f^ 我爸跟我求婚那天的事幔
I was gonna say, did I ever tell you about the day my dad proposed to my mom?
]有
No.
爸正在要去跟我求婚的路上
Well, Dad was on his way to meet my mom to propose,
撞了他的前女友卡_琳哈普
and he runs into his ex-girlfriend, Caroline Hopper.
他交著，  看著Ψ
And they're talking, they're looking at each other,
那些f感情突然又浮F
and all these old feelings, they start coming up.
他_始想
And he's thinking,
(SIGHS)
「我F在可以c卡_琳哈普私奔
"I could run away right now with Caroline Hopper,
「做快返娜
"be a happy man.
「我只需要吻她」
"All I have to do is kiss her."
但是他s抬起^
But instead, he looks up,
看到我霓D角走^
and he sees my mom walking around the corner.
那x那他明白了自己]什N好峙碌
And that moment he knows that he had no reason to be afraid.
你懂幔
You understand?
我在@故事中是卡_琳哈普 是你？
Am I Caroline Hopper in this story or your mom?
(EMILY GASPS)
天啊！我是你！
Oh, my God! I'm your mom!
-艾蜜莉，  今早看你r… -威，  拜
-Emily, when I saw you this morning... -Will, please.
-…我知道… -把那放回你的口袋Y
-... I knew... -Put that back in your pocket.
-站起恚  威，  停止 -…一切都很清晰
-Just stand up, Will. Stop. -...with absolute clarity.
-等等 -我]有理由峙
-Wait, wait, wait. -I have no reason to be afraid.
-我 -我不害怕
-Let's think about this. -I'm not afraid of this.
就像是那天我…
It's just like the day that my...
威！
Will!
我跟查理上了床！
I slept with Charlie!
(BIRDS FLUTTERING)
(SIGHS)
我以槲有
I thought we had a plan.
威，  是你有，  威 你有很大的！
Well, you had a plan, Will. You have a really big plan!
-我M_定是我z的 -我o法^m假b
-Pretty sure we both had that plan. -I just can't keep pretending
-自己想成橛的一部份 -的r候
-that I want to be part of it anymore. -You were there
-你也在 -我不知道如何跟你f
-when we made it. -And I didn't know how to tell you.
如何去跟你在乎的人
How do you tell someone that you care about
f你要的c他要的
that you don't want the same things
-已不同 -最好的方式幔
-they want anymore? -The best way?
^κ桥c他的室友上床
Definitely having sex with the roommate.
(SIGHS)
很]N，  我很抱歉
It was cowardly, and I'm sorry.
真好
Oh, good.
(GROANING)
你我好痛苦
You're killing me.
不，  我]有，  我放你走
No, I'm not. I'm letting you go.
因槲若^m在一起，  威 彼此都痛苦
'Cause if we stay together, Will, we're gonna be miserable.
我妨K你追求你那些…
I'm gonna hold you back from all these...
-才不是@ -…ゴ蟮粝
-That's not true. -...incredible dreams that you have.
最後你因此而恨我
And then, eventually, you're totally gonna hate me for it.
不 -
-No. -Yes.
威，  你我都不希望@
Will, I don't want that, and you don't want that.
相信我
Trust me.
你]事的，  海s先生
You're gonna be just fine, Mr. Hayes,
就算]有我
without me.
W
Wow.
是啊
Yeah.
W
Wow.
姆布洛考在~s
ANNOUNCER: Here is Tom Brokaw in New York.
晚安，  比柯林D或S在~s受
Good evening. Bill Clinton may have been wounded in New York,
但}是，害有多深呢？
but the big question tonight is, to what degree?
竟他存活了
Because, after all, he is the big survivor, indeed, the victor
p易的A得了~s初x
in the New York primary and by a comfortable margin.
(UPBEAT MUSIC PLAYING)
A僬-~s州c堪_斯州 柯林D
(TOM CHATTERING ON TV)
@月亮
WOMEN: (SINGING) Goes 'round the moon
我看你眼中的崆
I see the passion in your eyes
有rs完全是@喜
Sometimes it's all a big surprise
因槲以
'Cause there was a time when all I did
(ALL CHATTERING)
嘿
Hey.
恭喜
Congratulations.
我f他要求你留下 你一定很_心吧
I hear they asked you to stay on. You must be very happy.
嗯，  他的_，  我是，  非常、非常快
Yeah, yeah, he did, and I am. Very, very happy.
真的？楹挝矣X得 我⒌镀都藏起恚
Really? Why do I feel like I should hide the razor blades?
有Cc那些剪刀？
And the staplers and those scissors?
我]事的 但@首歌真是人想死啊
I'll be fine. But this song, it's an excellent cure for the will to live.
我知道，  那跳舞的那些呢？ 他停止吧
I know. What about the dancing? Make that end.
(CHUCKLES)
那晚很抱歉
I'm sorry about the other night.
]PS，  我只是想R卡斯 不很高d
It's okay. I just didn't think that Lucas would approve.
-艾蜜莉也是 -嗯
-Or Emily, for that matter. -(SCOFFS) Well.
r且，  我在一起一定像c狗
Besides, you and me, it'd kind of be like cats and dogs.
Α
Yeah. Yeah.
-油c水 -沙c光屁屁
-Oil and water. -Sandpaper and bare ass.
-好f心，  有f心 -屁屁是你
-That's gross. That's just gross. -You'd be the ass.
嗯，  不，  多x了
Yeah. No, thank you.
-我太s幸了 -{zc卡尼
-I'd be honored. -Lennon and McCartney.
-他z很合 -b有一子
-They were good together. -Yeah, while it lasted,
然後就B朋友都做不成
and then they couldn』t even be friends.
(LAUGHING)
-我想那方面我]} -我也是@N想
-I think we can, at least, manage that. -I think we could.
(WOMAN LAUGHING)
-幸 -乾杯
-Enchante. -Yeah. Salud.
-走嘛，  我去跳舞 -不要
-Come on, let's dance. -No.
-槭颤N？ -好啦
-Why? -Okay.
-浜昧幔 -嗯
You ready?  Yeah.
艾蜜莉就@恿税
Guess that's it for Emily.
女朋友-特|
我真不敢相信她c查理
I can't believe that she rehearsed with Charlie.
-我也不敢相信 -那就剩艾波，  或S是夏曼
-I can't believe it, either. -That leaves April. Maybe Summer.
-有人幔 -我太忙了
-Anybody else? -I was too busy.
榱烁x忙得要死
I was too busy working on the campaign.
反正，  柯林Dx後
Anyway, when Clinton got elected,
_素c我成立了一家公司
Russell and I started our own consulting firm,
(CAMERA CLICKING)
我痛蠹腋x
and we worked on campaigns for everybody.
市hT、州hT
City council, state senate.
甚至附近抓狗的
We even did one for the local dog catcher.
很有趣，  爸，  但那些女友呢？
That's very interesting, Dad, but what about girlfriends?
-呢？ -我又_始s
-What about Mom? -Well, I started dating again.
-但不是很J真 -艾波呢？她怎N恿耍
-But nothing serious. -What about April? What happened to her?
嗯，  柯特寇本死了一周後 她c男友分手了
Well, a week after Kurt Cobain died, she broke up with her boyfriend.
她跑去旅行
She went traveling.
h[世界，  F了她的粝
She traveled all over the world, just like she always dreamed of doing.
她f是因
And she says that it was because of something
我在她生日r跟她f^的
that I said to her on her birthday.
我先互名信片，  然後_始通信
Anyway, we started writing postcards. We started writing letters.
不知不X中，  m然我相隔f里
And before I knew it, even though we were separated by entire worlds,
我成了好朋友
we became great friends.
《邸
1994年，  ~s充M生
It was 1994, and New York was full of new life.
更多的工作c富
More jobs, more money.
敬期待W路！
That was the start of the Internet. And overnight, everyone in Manhattan
那是W路的_始 在一夜之g，  所有曼哈D的人
都拿著手C
had a cell phone.
得到我幔
Can you hear me now?
KC不x手
Which they never put down.
然後我的f上司瑟_牙锥 o了_素和我千dy逢的C
And then, our old boss, Arthur Robredo gave Russell and me our first big break.
-@是o你的 -xx
-This just came for you. -Thanks.
我K於跨M了那扇T
I had finally made it inside the room.
-w瑞斯 -海s
-Gareth. -Hayes.
早安
Good morning.
嘿，  上工_
Hey, let's get this party started.
北部那怎樱
What's the word from upstate?
生平第一次，  ~s的大^主碚椅
For the first time, New York was coming to me,
而不是我去求他
instead of the other way around.
一切下滑
「我最lR^N的
"The most endangered species in our nation
「不是大啄木B或是什N淡水~
"isn't a big woodpecker or some freshwater fish.
「而是我X中的Z言！
"It's the tongue in our heads!
「今@些不成的Z言
"Listen to the truncated bastard language of today.
「平均~≈皇Ｒ话倌昵暗娜分之一
"The average vocabulary is a third of what it was 100 years ago.
「才f出口就死於_前！
"Words fall out of our mouths and die at our feet!
「~〉倪h景被屠宰
"The landscape of vocabulary is being hacked down
「被流行文化扭曲得不不
"and grubbed up by the dribble of pop culture,
「K遭猩⒌囊x玷污…」
"poisoned by lazy obscenity..."
威？
(WHISPERING) Will?
「…被崇拜年p的媒w夯…」
HAMPTON: "...infantilized by a youth-obsessed media..."
-嘿 -嘿
-Hey. -Hey.
是我最喜g的小毛^ 你看沓墒於嗔
It's my favorite man-boy. You look very manly.
xx、xx，  我是@N打算的啦
Well, thank you, thank you. That's the aim.
-艾蜜莉如何？ -艾蜜莉
-How's Emily? -Emily.
她F在是e人日Y的女主角了
She's starring in somebody else』s diary now.
Oh.
-教授如何？ -教授很好
-How's the Professor? -The Professor is wonderful.
-他很搞笑 -榱大二生甩了我
-He's funny. -He dumped me for a sophomore.
跟我f是槲液
Told me it was for my own good.
最近好像很流行@句
Everybody seems to be using that line these days.
你最近都在致铮
What have you been up to?
汀都~ssI》些很蠢的|西
I'm writing these really dumb items for New York Magazine.
等著熬出^
Waiting for my big break.
「而「Z法」不是热A_州的妓院 付o局的
"And 'syntax' isn't what Nevada brothels pay the IRS."
(AUDIENCE LAUGHING)
-我去教授演v -好啊
-I'm gonna go listen to the Professor. -Sure.
眼R很好看
Nice glasses.
「有C去你的孩子f」
HAMPTON: "Listen to your kids if you can."
-xx -麻┩士忌加冰
Thank you.  Scotch, rocks, please.
威廉海s！
William Hayes!
是摹e告V我！
From... Don't tell me!
威斯康辛州淼模Γ  乳酪a地
Wisconsin! Yes, the Cheese State.
很高d你能⒓游@小聚
Very nice of you to come to our little shindig.
-麻┰硪槐 -我的s幸
-I'll have another, please. -PIeasure.
嗯，  夏曼跟我f 你在瑟_牙锥v稿？
Yeah. Summer tells me you're writing speeches now for Arthur Robredo?
-她跟我f你的新女友是大二生 -不，  其是大一生
-She tells me you're dating a sophomore. -No. Actually, it's two freshmen,
情r好r可成一大二生吧
which, on a good day, add up to a sophomore, I suppose.
陪我走走，  你怎N 瑟_牙锥噙@N政客u力？
WaIk with me. Why would you wanna work for a hack like Arthur Robredo?
我得我初次面r 你是有原tc抱的人
As I recall from our first encounter, you're a man of principles and ideals, even.
e跟我f你也只是另一 穿著曼尼西b的雅痞
Don't tell me you're just another yuppie puppy in an Armani suit.
你v得好好，  H鄣 他有Y幔磕λ有Y幔
You were wonderful, darling. Is he being nice? You being nice?
-有Y？他得住的 -然，  我得住
-Nice? Yeah, he can handle himself. -Sure, I can handle myself.
首先，  瑟_牙锥嗖皇钦客 他是幕幼銎鸬
First of all, Arthur Robredo is not a hack. He's worked his way up from the streets.
他曾是警察、I家
He was a cop, an entrepreneur.
他是白V，  我的的主}就是@
He's a putz. This is exactly what my book is about.
拿去，  xx吧，  免M的
Here. Read it. It's free.
美、理想、鄱家晃牟恢
Beauty, ideals, love don't mean squat anymore.
-重要的只是嗔εc金X -你的每本我都拜x^
-It's all about power and money. -I've read every single one of your books,
而你才完全嗔εc金X著迷
and you're completely obsessed with power and money.
那是因樗烧叨]有 是吧，  ？
That's because he doesn't have any. Right, babe?
，  我最在乎的是
Babe, I am about the love.
-你知道的 -
-As you know. -Yes.
所以你才留我在身
That's why you keep me around.
好管住你那又野又婪的野心
To keep that rampant, rapacious ambition of yours in check.
我有想法
I have a thought.
你不如利用你那一丁c的 嗔εc影力
Why don't you use that newly acquired scintilla of power and influence
夏曼湍隳橇_牙锥嗟砘 篇文章？
to get Summer here to write an article about your man Robredo?
@右恚  能夏曼出^ 你也能散播你的信息
That way Summer gets a break, and you get the word out.
-你得到了什N呢，  h普D？ -是啊
-What do you get, Hampton? -Yeah.
我想是郯桑  更多的 我就只在乎@
I guess it's the love. More of the love. Yeah, that's what I'm about.
更多
More love.
-我就知道夏曼再出F -是幔
- I knew Summer would be back. -Did you?
你知道幔课乙婚_始 K不希望夏曼是我母H
You know what? At first, I didn't want Summer to be my mom.
但我F在M喜g她的 你有s她出去幔
But now I'm kinda liking her. Did you ask her out on a date?
Uh-uh.
我很想，  但我不能 因槲恼鲁鲎运P
I wanted to, but I couldn』t 'cause she was writing the article.
_牙锥楹o法言慎行 ~s打舴缸镨F腕的民主hT
-W，  得真不e -威，  @篇很棒
-Wow. This is pretty good. -Will, this is really good.
(DIALING)
你_定不像拍R屁的文章？
SUMMER: Are you sure it didn't seem like a puff piece?
不，很完美，  完全…
No, it's perfect. It's absolutely...
不^有一部份我有c困_
You know, there's one part, though, that kind of bothered me.
「威廉海s
"William Hayes,
_牙锥嘀饕的v稿作者 不H嵴Kв屑真的
"Robredo's chief speech writer, is both intense and boyishly handsome."
-真？我是f… -
-Boyishly? I mean... -Yeah.
(GRUNTS)
我本硎
You know, I originally wrote,
「威廉海s有著一p勾人的p眼 c吸引人的L相
"William Hayes has seductive eyes and the intriguing looks of someone
「人想光他的衣服」
"whose clothes you wanna rip from his very body,"
但是逼我改掉
but the editor made me change it.
新界已]有事存活的空g了
There's just no room for truth in journalism.
你一直都想要成橛者幔
Did you always want to be a journalist?
不，  16q之前我一直想演T 我想在百老R唱歌
No. Until I was 16, I wanted to be an actress. I wanted to sing on Broadway.
W，  真的？
Wow. Really?
是啊，  真的，很y以置信幔
Yeah, really. Is that hard to believe?
嗯，  女演T不都O度需要P注 很情w化K]有安全感幔
Well, aren't actresses needy and emotional and, you know, insecure?
都那
That sort of thing.
你想f什N？我不需要P注？ 我]有情w幔
What are you saying? That I don't need? That I don't have emotions?
-我是非常需要P注的人 -我不是@意思
-I'm an incredibly needy person. -I'm not saying that.
-我很需要P注 -你懂我想f什N幔
-I'm a very needy person. -You know what I'm saying?
我是f我想一首歌
I'm saying I would love to hear a song.
-抱歉？ -硎赘璋
-I'm sorry? -Give us a song.
-你要我槟愠歌 -有何不可？
-You want me to sing you a song? -Why not?
-你有最喜g的歌幔 -有
-You have a favorite? -Yes.
-有喔？ -是啊
-You do? -Yeah.
好吧
Okay.
(CLEARING THROAT)
世上成千上f的
(SINGING) How glad the many millions
提摩西c威廉⒍帱N快
Of Timothys and Williams would be
-我也是威廉之一 -e打岔
-I'm a William. -Don't interrupt.
若他捕@我
To capture me
但你如此的讨
But you had such persistence
磨去了我的防
You wore down my resistance
我入了
I fell
感X真好
And it was swell
不是因槟憧∏
It's not that you're attractive
W
Wow.
能求你Q上它幔
Will you please put it on?
真的不不好看
You know, it really isn't so bad.
但你知道有趣的是什N幔 它要一千元
You know what the funny part is? It's $1,000.
我迷僦你，  甜心
I've got a crush on you, sweetie pie
法m克辛{屈、琳_朗z黛
Frank Sinatra, Linda Ronstadt.
-槭颤N？ -一大堆
-Why? A whole bunch of these.
若你看看後面 它都有一共同的歌，  就是…
Well, if you look on the back, they all have one common song, which is...
-  《我迷僦你》 -每一都有
-I've Got A Crush On You. -Every one of them.
-M度如何？ -有很多要做
-How's it going? -Still got a lot to do.
我也是
Yeah, me, too.
-嗯，  我差不多了 -嗯，  我也是
-Yeah, I'm about done. -Yeah, me, too.
@世界原我的崆
The world will pardon my mush
因槲颐僦，  我的
'Cause I've got a crush, my baby, on...
我打鼾幔
Was I snoring?
Uh-uh.
你知道我]^什N幔
You know what I've never done?
什N？
What?
我]跟好男人在床上一整天^
I've never spent the whole day in bed with a really great guy.
我也是
Me, neither.
我f真的
I'm serious.
我是想著有更重要的事要做
I always think of something more important to do.
我是工作狂
(WHISPERS) I'm a workaholic.
(WILLIAM EXCLAIMS)
很糟糕
It's really bad.
你意跟我在床上一天幔
Will you spend the whole day in bed with me?
我什N都不做
We do nothing.
(PHONE RINGING)
Oh.
(PHONE CONTINUES RINGING)
(ANSWERING MACHINE CLICKS)
嗨，  @是夏曼，  留言，  我回
Hi, this is Summer. Please leave a message, and I will call you back.
(ANSWERING MACHINE BEEPS)
我是R文史坦t
This is Dr. Levenstein
@是哥比 基督L老教t院的急\室，  我…
from the Columbia Presbyterian emergency room. We have...
急\室？喂？
Emergency room? Hello?
-_斯先生的大用}破裂 -那究竟是什N意思？
-Mr. Roth has had an aortal rupture. -What does that mean exactly?
就像是在高速公路上
Think of it like a tire blowing out on the highway
_得太快、太久後突然爆胎
after going too fast for way too long.
(HEART MONITOR BEEPING)
怎N樱  _斯先生？可以幔
How's that, Mr. Roth? Are you comfortable?
我得
I make a living.
(BOTH SNIGGERING)
拜，  甜心，  笑一嘛 我一子都在等著v@笑
Come on, sweetheart, give me a smile. I've waited my whole life to do that joke.
可z的h普D
Poor Hampton.
Ow!
夏曼砹
Summer's come.
-他致铮 -你好，  h普D
-What's he doing here? -Hello, Hampton.
你好
Hello.
(CHATTERING ON PHONE)
(SUMMER LAUGHING)
就只剩@]挨他的刀
One thing they've left intact.
不、不、不，  e提到草根政治\
No, no, no, no, no, no, don't mention grassroots.
e提到同化
Don't mention osmosis.
你跟那小鬼在一起我很困_
It's killing me that you're going out with the kid.
真的？不是酒c大二生？
Really? It's not the booze or the cigarettes or the sophomores?
-跟那一cPS都]有 -一cPS都]有
-That has nothing to do with this. -Nothing to do with it.
著，  我要你知道 我⑵鞴俣季栀ot研究
Listen, I want you to know I've donated my organs to medical science
除了一，  是留o你的
except for one, which is for you.
-甜心，  你真好 -不，  不是那
-Sweetie, that's so kind. -No, no, not that.
是我的心，  傻瓜
My heart, stupid.
(LAUGHING)
告V我你]有凵纤
Please tell me you're not in love with him.
我不能
I can't do that.
(SIGHS)
能o我支幔颗R死前最後的望
Can I have a cigarette? Just a dying man's last request.
e想了，  天啊，  你真的很歇斯底里
Not happening. God, you're such a drama queen.
]人要死了
Nobody's dying.
你又怎在乎我鄄鬯呢？
What do you care if I'm in love with him, huh?
是你介B我JR的，  得幔
You're the one who set us up, remember?
是啊，  但我本以槟玩玩他就算了
Yeah, well, I kind of figured you'd chew him up and spit him out.
你真是好人，  你好帖心喔 你知道幔
You're such a sweetie. You're a sweet guy, you know that?
-我x了_牙锥嗟哪瞧 -是喔
-I read the Robredo piece. -Yeah.
那砘恼了20多年
The guy's been in New York politics for over 20 years
你s只挖得出他女菏秋食疾患？
and all you can dig up is that his daughter had an eating disorder?
你想f什N，  h普D？
What are you saying, Hampton?
做好你的工作
Do your job.
(CAR HORNS HONKING)
每日新 柯林D支持_牙锥
I can't believe we're finally gonna meet the President.
我真不敢相信我K於要y
-你看看 -你看看
-Look at that. -Look at it.
我可不是年 在第8街小旅^那人了
We've come a long way from that hotel room on 8th Avenue.
非常感x
Thank you very much.
我不敢相信！我不敢相信！
GARETH: I don't believe it! I don't believe it!
哪白V忘了z查菜魏统绦虮恚
Which idiot forgot to check the menus and the programmes?
菜闻c程序表上都]有工的徽章
There's no union seal on the menus or the programmes.
真的假的？
Are you serious?
店T工不任何人M
The hotel workers won't let anybody into the building.
卡司C工的人不肯架l星饔！
The Teamsters won't set up the satellite feed!
有人看到_伯特克R幔
Has anyone seen Robert Klein?
我一小r前才看到他 F在人就不了
I was with him like an hour ago. Now he's gone.
他好像喝炝
I think he was completely plastered.
我怎N知道_伯特克R在哪？
How are we supposed to know where Robert Klein is?
你不相信的，  但芝加哥雹暴
You're not gonna believe this, but there's a hailstorm in Chicago.
l管芝加哥啊？
Who cares about Chicago?
我啊，  y要闹ゼ痈
We do. The President's coming in from Chicago.
-好、好 -我F在]k法管@
-Okay, okay. -We can't worry about that right now.
我你，  你怎@N事l生？
Let me ask you a question. How could you let this happen?
-什N？你在f什N？ -你槭颤Nn著她？
-What? What are you talking about? -Why are you jumping down her throat?
等等、等等！ 大家、大家、大家！
Whoa, whoa, whoa! Guys, guys, guys, guys, hey!
嘿，  深呼吸好幔课去店
Hey, deep breath, okay? Look, let's just ask the hotel,
看能不能用他的W路K找印表C
see if we can use the Internet connection and find a printer.
-我去打o克R的理人 -很好
-I'll call Klein』s agent. -Great.
w瑞斯，  砗纫槐
Gareth, have a drink.
你，  我不知道你是l 但你的拉]拉
You, I don't know who you are, but your fly』s down.
你若能穿妊的就太好了 我去查芝加哥的天
Be great if you wore underwear. I'm gonna go check the weather in Chicago.
第7桌可以上菜了 6份意大利面、煞蒴~，  快送上去！
Table seven's up. Six pasta. Two fish. Get it out the door, now!
(COMPUTER BEEPING)
(SIGHS)
(STATIC BUZZING)
他或S不是你工的
He may not be in your union,
但他仍是美y
but he still happens to be the President of the United States.
得他幔咳粑沂悄
Remember him? So if I was you,
-我就叫你的人下KM怼 -w瑞斯！
-I'd get your men off that truck and in this... -Gareth!
你不能@痈卡工的人f！ 拜
You can't talk to a Teamster like that! Come on.
-@砘铩 -]事的
-This guy... -Everything's gonna be fine.
你看看
Look, look, check it out.
我下d了工的徽章
I downloaded a copy of the union seal.
麻┠闾在菜紊
If you could just please paste it onto a menu,
去影印五百份，  找家有工的店 我就安了
make 500 copies, use a union shop. We're gonna be home free, here.
影印？你要我去影印？
Copies? You want me to make copies?
(ELEVATOR DINGS)
每人都有某r期要去影印 F在到你了
Well, at some point, we all make copies. Your time is now.
不好笑，  海s，  那很…
That's not funny, Hayes. That's very...
嗯，  真成熟，  你要去哪？
Yeah, that's real mature. Where are you going?
我去散步！半小r後回
I'm walking! Back in half an hour.
王八蛋
What a dick.
(CELL PHONE RINGING)
-喂 -威廉海s？
-Yeah. - (WHISPERING) William Hayes?
我就是
Speaking.
我F在正盯著你
I'm watching you right now.
我很清楚你c你朋友_牙锥嗟氖
And I know all about you and your friend Robredo.
我甚至可以Я四扇
In fact, I know so much, I could bring you both down.
真的？
Really?
-你是？ -不如我面，  你就知道了？
-Who am I speaking with? -Why don't we meet, and you'll find out?
-你在哪？ -x你很近
-Where are you? -I'm close by.
我@]什N
I don't have a lot of experience with whatever this is.
你越碓浇咏
You're getting warm.
很近
You're hot.
你好正！
You are so hot!
(APRIL LAUGHING)
_到你了！
I got you!
我以槟阏夏天都不在
I thought you were gone through the summer.
不，  我原本也@酉 但是l生了件很狂的事
No, I thought so, too, but this crazy thing happened.
我在克里特u美的沙漠露I
I mean, I was camping on this beautiful beach in Crete
跟一群很酷的人 其中有我喜g的男的叫派克
with all these really cool people, and there was this guy that I liked, Paco,
深沉又性感，  很少，  完全是我的型
brooding and sexy, monosyllabic and totally my type.
有天晚上我c派克跳舞r，  他吻了我
One night I'm dancing with Paco and he kisses me,
-很深很棒的一吻 -e跟我f
-an incredible, deep kiss. - Spare me the details.
-你知道我怎N幔 -不知道，  你怎樱
And what do I do? -I don't know. What'd you do?
我_始哭
I start crying.
-眼I就一直流下a… -你然哭
-I mean, tears are rolling down my cheeks... -Of course you start crying.
…Y果他]lX 因樗的手忙著在我身上[走
...which he doesn't notice 'cause, of course, his hands are all over my body,
感X很好，  但s我更y^
which felt nice, which made me feel even more upset,
突然g
'cause in a flash
我眼前晃^了 我F在到未黹g的偾
I saw our entire relationship, from present to future tense.
很火岬拈_始，  派克享受著我的邸
I mean, the incredibly hot start, with Paco basking in my love and admiration...
-我磉@致铮 -我需要拿|西
-What are we doing here? -I just got to pick something up.
一下就好
Just take a second.
然後不可避免的一刻 我也不知道槭颤N…
And then the inevitable moment, and I don't know why it...
-哈_ -嗨
-Hello. -Hi.
我也不知道槭颤N@ 但是每次都@
I don't know why it happens, but it always does,
那些㈤_始令他
when all that love and admiration would start to irritate him
然後他就害我
and he'd find some way to hurt me.
他事後然感到很抱歉
I mean, sure, after, he'd be sorry.
所以…
So...
我Q定x他美的唇
I decided to unlock his beautiful lips from mine,
⑺[在我屁股上的手移_
remove his hand from my ass,
(LAUGHS)
-然後走_ -值煤
-and I walked away. -Good move.
-我x_了，  威！x_派克！ -值煤
-I walked away, Will! From Paco! -Good move.
-]有人能抗拒派克！ -我喜g@故事
-No one walks away from Paco! -I like the story.
感X像是扭D了命\
And it felt life-changing.
我lX我得跟人分享
And I realized I had to tell someone.
我意R到@人是lr
When I realized who that person was,
-好出乎意料 -在@Y，  先生
-it was so unexpected. - Here we are, sir.
像是有什N直著你
It's like when something is staring you in the face
但你s盲目得看不
and it's like you're too blind to see it.
那是什N？
What's that?
我也有事要δ阏f
I have some news for you, too.
等等、等等，  你槭颤N@N生猓
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa. Why are you so upset?
你不X得在我通了@N久的信後
Don't you think it's a little weird we've been writing each other for however long
你竟然]跟我透露
and somehow you neglect to tell me that,
一、你哿耍  二、你居然哿
A, you've fallen in love, and, B, you've fallen in love!
-我跟你f^我在s -s
-I told you I was dating someone. -Dating someone.
你才腿思屹I了婚戒指！
You just bought a diamond engagement ring for someone!
抱歉，  我於要跟你f感到o
I'm sorry. I think I was just nervous to tell you.
槭颤N跟我f你o？
Why would you be nervous to tell me?
不知道
I don't know.
我好圻@女孩
I love this girl so much.
我很希望你能槲腋吲d
I'd just really like you to be happy for me.
我可以槟愀吲d 我然可以槟愀吲d
I can be happy for you. Of course I can be happy for you.
可z的艾波
Poor April.
她就像是故事Y永h是朋友的那角色
She's like the character in the story who's always been the friend.
然後lF她不想只做朋友
Then she realized she doesn't just want to be the friend.
她其想女朋友，  但是太t了
She wants to be the girlfriend, except it's too late.
什N意思？
What do you mean?
你]在幔克榱四慊
Weren't you listening? She came home for you.
所有的菜紊隙加谢照拢老友
GARETH: There's union seals on all the menus, my friend.
芝加哥的天夥徘缌耍  y8c到
The weather cleared in Chicago. The President will be here by 8:00.
小_呢？
Where's Russ?
他在餐dc你和瑟碰面
Gonna meet you and Arthur in the restaurant.
我在@比^好笑
ROBERT KLEIN: I'm funnier over here.
(HARMONICA PLAYING)
我腿停不住
I can't stop my leg
你早到了
You're early.
(MOANING)
到你真好
Good to see you.
-你看砗芎 -xx，  你也是
-You look great. -Thank you. You, too.
-IШ芷亮 -你最清楚了
-That's a nice tie. -Well, you'd know.
sI社要我^m跟_牙锥嗟
So, the magazine asked me to do a follow-up on Robredo.
-很好 -嗯，  是很好，  但也…
-Great. -Yeah, it is great. It's also...
也…
(SIGHING) It's...
你自己看吧
You just read it.
-你已好了 -嗯
-You already wrote it. -Yeah.
-他做了@事？ -是的
-He did this? -Yes.
他一朋友提早假
They actually got a friend an early parole.
你知道幔窟@是好久以前的事了
You know what? I think it happened such a long time ago,
你的卷{查又I先@N多
and you're way ahead in all the polls.
嗯，  @λ税袷氰F腕打舴缸锏 民主hT不有什N大影
Yeah, see, I don't think that's gonna matter, because he's the tough-on-crime Democrat.
那…
That's...
人x了@…
When people read this...
夏曼，  我f
Summer, listen to me.
你若交了上去，  我就完了
If you hand this in, we won't survive it.
我X得被炒作一Y拜 然後L暴就^了…
I think it'll be a big deal for about a week, and then the storm will pass...
我是f我z
I'm talking about you and me.
「候x人ъ吨v稿作者之女友」
"Candidate Brought Down by Speechwriter's GirIfriend."
-拜 -我只是在做我的工作
-Come on. -I'm just doing my job.
我第一次rK]有M
I didn't do it the first time around.
就算我不也有人
And if I didn't write this, somebody else would.
他
Let them.
嘿，  e交上去，  好幔
Hey, don't hand this in, okay?
你已交了
You already did.
瑟先生…
Mr. Arthur...
(CHATTERING)
好的
ARTHUR: Yeah, sure.
我真的很喜g夏曼
I really liked Summer.
我真不敢相信她竟然如此…
I can't believe she turned out to be such a...
-人心碎？ -不
-Heartbreaker? -No.
投C者？背叛…
-Opportunist? Double-crossing... -Uh-uh.
-v人 -雅
-Bitch. -Maya.
她怎N能@δ悖
How could she do that to you?
就如她所f，  她要是不 也有e人去
It's like she said. If she didn't write it, someone else would have.
而且那是事
And it was the truth.
她有幔克你心碎幔
So did she? Did she break it?
什N？
What?
文章登出後呢？
What happened when the article came out?
《~s日蟆罚  他出局了！
你搞砸了，老兄，  你真的搞砸了
You screwed up, man. You really screwed up.
省省吧，  我F在不想你f教
Please save it. I don't need to hear this right now.
等我搞清楚@件事 Ыo我什N教r
Whenever I figure out whatever I'm supposed to learn from all this,
-我通知你的 -我迫不及待
-I'll write you a letter! -Yeah, can't wait.
我失去了女友、工作、朋友
So I lost my girl, I lost my job, and I lost my friend.
有好L一段rg，  一切彷范疾恢匾
And for a long time, nothing seemed to matter.
但世上有}的不只是我
But I wasn't the only one with problems.
我c那女人之g]有性PS
I did not have sexual relations with that woman,
文斯基小姐
Miss Lewinsky.
我奈匆求e人撒e
I never told anybody to lie.
-喂？ -你在看幔
-Hello? -Are you watching?
@些指控是e`的
These allegations are false.
艾波？
April?
嗯，  是艾波？你以槭钦l？ 你到底有]有在看？
Yeah, April. Who'd you think it was? Are you watching or not?
然在看
Of course I'm watching.
你X得他做了吧？
You think he did it, don't you?
我不用X得，  我知道 你看她的照片，  我鬯
I don't think, I know. Look at the picture of her. I love her.
她超像他的型
She's so his type.
你槭颤N@N久才回我，  小t？
So, what took you so long to finally call me back there, red?
我以槲沂去你了
I thought I lost you.
-感X好像好啄炅 -我F在不是打o你了幔
-Feels like years. -I'm calling you now, aren't I?
嗯
Yeah.
你好幔慷荚谧鲂┦颤N？
How are you? What's doing?
我多了室友，  W莉微雅
I got a new roommate, Olivia.
我在店做事
And I'm working at a bookstore.
本凫栋虐爬克 夏G蒂白朗特著《邸
但我一直在想要不要回去
But I've been thinking about going back to school.
酷
Cool.
嘿，  我有f我痛恨我的工作幔
Hey, did I tell you that I hate my job?
我以前好畚业墓ぷ 但我F在X得自己像_子
I used to love what I do, and now I feel like a complete hack.
海s先生：抱歉，  但@本《邸肥醉K]有}~，  需要^m找幔
-你交女朋友了幔 -我？我交…不，  完全]有
-Are you seeing anyone? -Me? Am I... No, no. Absolutely not.
我目铝诸DB任後就]做^了
In fact, I haven't had sex since Clinton was re-elected.
何必M事呢？他⑷的~度都包了
Why bother? He's having enough sex for the entire country.
e@N缺德
Easy. Easy now.
嘿，  或S你跟S他的_步 去勾引生
Hey, maybe you should follow his lead and seduce an intern.
你提到@真巧
You know, it's funny that you should mention that.
上Y拜才砹很正的生
There's a fetching young intern who just started a week ago.
很好，  s她出去啊
Great. Ask her out.
我_，  是幔
I should, shouldn't I?
但我想不吧，  我不想只是玩玩
But I don't think I will. You see, I don't want a fling.
我要的是真
I want the real deal.
e管什N真哿耍  真塾刹坏媚闳フ 它自己找上T
Forget about the real deal. You don't find it, it finds you.
什N意思？我不懂@其中的意思
What does that mean? I don't know what that means.
意思就是等你年o到了K浜r
It means that you get to a certain age and then you're ready.
就是你浜蒙孩子或是o承Z 或者是…
You know, you're ready for kids or a commitment or, you know...
-先生 -…背房J
-Sir. -...a mortgage.
-位子浜昧 -xx
-Table』s ready. Okay. -Thanks.
懂幔
You know what I mean?
r跟你在一起的人 就是你的真命天子
And the person that you're with then, they become the one.
你的意思是不是人的} 而是rC_？
So you're saying it's not who, but it's when.
-正是 -好吧
-Exactly. -Okay. All right.
所以奈从男的你X得 「就是@
So there's never been a guy, ever, that made you think, "This is it.
「就是他了，  他是真命天子」
"This is him. This is the one."
]有
No.
好，  那你槭颤N不出去玩呢？
Okay, then why aren't you out there, you know, enjoying yourself?
我有啊
I am.
-你有？ -
-You are? -Yes.
我F在c一叫P文的s
Right now I'm seeing this guy, Kevin.
-P文 -P文
-Kevin. -Kevin.
P文他的是l啊？
Who the hell's Kevin?
哪淼摹你怎N]提^他？
Where did... How come you never, you know, mentioned anything about him?
我F在不是在提
I'm mentioning him now.
天啊！他@有新r的薄荷茶 我最郾『刹枇
Oh, God! They have fresh mint tea. I love fresh mint tea.
我燮【
I love beer.
那要看「是」的定x楹瘟
It depends upon what the meaning of the word "is" is.
若意思是「是]有」 @句完全的真
If it means "there is none" that is a completely true statement.
(BEEPS)
嘿，  是艾波
(ON ANSWERING MACHINE) Hey, this is April.
我要跟你你生日的事，  打o我
I want to talk to you about your birthday. Call me.
(BEEPS)
哈_，  希望@是Φ奶a 起硐袷悄愕穆音
Hello. I hope this is the right number. It sounds like you.
我是艾蜜莉！
It's Emily!
(LAUGHS)
我人在~s，  我在想
I'm in New York, and I was thinking
或S我可以喝杯咖啡、⑴f
maybe we could get a cup of coffee and catch up.
我的a是…
My number...
(BEEPS)
嘿，  是艾波，  我是需要跟你聊 回
Hey, it's April. I still need to talk to you. Please call me back.
e逼我^去扁你
I mean, don't make me come over there and hurt you.
(DOORBELL BUZZING)
好啦，  我砹
Okay, I'm coming!
天啊，  砹
God, I'm coming.
嗯，  知道了
Yeah, I get it.
你在Y面致铮
What are you doing in there?
-你就穿@樱 -什N？
-Is this what you're wearing? -What?
是你的生日派Γ  大家都在等你
It's your birthday party. Everybody is waiting for you.
天啊
Oh, Christ.
五分，  好幔课濉
Five minutes, okay? Five...
(CRASHING)
-我摔倒了 -]事吧？
- I'm down. -Are you okay?
嗯，  我只需要躺一下
Yeah. I just need to lie here for a sec.
(GROANS)
看砟阌性诔渣I
I see you've been eating noodles.
嘿，  大家，  他到了！
Hey, everybody, he's here!
(ALL CHEERING)
x了
Thanks.
嗨
Hi.
我的天！我]想到你也砹耍
Oh, my God! I didn't think you'd be here!
怎N能e^你生日 我特地娜A府s淼
I couldn』t miss your birthday. We came all the way up from Washington.
生日快罚  哥
Happy birthday, gorgeous.
@可是漂亮的女人
That is a beautiful woman right there.
你曾有C的
You had your chance, pal.
海s
Hayes.
^
Come on.
(RUSSELL LAUGHING)
-到你真好 -嗯，  你看怼
-It's great to see you. -Yeah. You look...
像[民，  我知道
Homeless, I know.
-P莉呢？ -她在那
-Where's Kelly? -She's right over there.
@是她在生後第一次出硗
It's her first night out since the baby was born.
恭喜你
Congratulations.
伊朗售、石油Q武器，  ]}
Iran-Contra. Arms for oil, no problem.
但一cc「嘴上功夫」就面R劾
But a little "oralness" and you're headed for impeachment.
-不政治 -或S他被劾
-No politics! -Maybe he should be impeached.
等等、等等！那是他f的幔
Whoa, whoa, whoa! Wait! Did he say that?
-槭颤N不？我相信他，  我都是 -你鬯
-Why not? I put my faith in him. We all did. -You love him.
我以樗跟其他那些小丑不同
I thought he was gonna be different than the other jokers,
但他B「是」@字都o法定x
but this guy, he can't even define the word "is."
要是他o他像「事」@N字呢？
What happens if they give him one of the hard words, like "truth"?
-我是x他 -想都不用想
-I'd vote for him again. -In a heartbeat.
威很好玩
Will's a lot of fun.
嗯，  不如我⒃韪追M水 然後再⒖军I包CGM去
Yeah, let's fill up the tub and drop in a toaster.
很好玩吧
That should be a good time.
祝你生日快
Happy birthday to you
祝H鄣耐生日快
Happy birthday, dear Will
-他呢？威呢？ -不知道，  在跟他f
-Where is he? Where's Will? -I don't know. I was just talking to him.
你e^了你的生日蛋糕
You missed your birthday cake.
Uh-oh.
-是我烤的 -你烤的
And I baked it. -You baked it.
你得那首歌幔
Do you remember that song?
在你的公寓？
In your apartment?
以朋友的身份前
Come as you are, as a friend
以宿
As a known enemy
-是「」不是「宿场 -我知道、我知道、我知道
-"Memory," not "enemy." -I know, I know, I know.
-有人喝多了 -我]有
-Somebody had too much to drink. -No, I didn't.
我]有、我]有、我]有
I didn't, I didn't. I didn't.
-有，  你有 -我有
-Yes, you did. -I did.
-天啊，  你好美 -xx
-God, you're beautiful. -Thank you.
什N？
What?
}是…
The thing is...
(CLEARS THROAT)
}是…
The thing is...
我喜g你
Is that I like you.
我一直都喜g你
I've always liked you.
「喜g」
"Like."
好可悲、好d的字眼
That's pathetic. It's so puny.
另一方面，  「邸埂
"Love" on the other hand...
到@N字眼你一定跑
You'd run away from a word like that.
我勰
I love you.
艾波，  我凵夏懔
I'm in love with you, April.
-你楹]告V^我？ -拜
-Why didn't you ever tell me? -Come on.
你知道我槭颤N]跟你f 你根本不看上我
You know exactly why I never told you. You'd never be interested in me.
你@白V
You're an idiot.
-住手 -什N？
-Stop. -What?
-不是@ -怎樱
-Not like this. -Like what?
你看你，  威，  你一F糟
Look at you, Will, you're a mess.
你好好的r候槭颤N不跟我f？
Why couldn』t you have told me when you had your shit together?
-我很好啊 -你一Fy
-My shit is together. -Your shit is a mess.
你一Fy
You're a mess.
我一Fy？
My shit is a mess?
艾波，  哪憧谥新到@句真有趣
That's interesting, coming from you, April.
你想做什N都可以，  但s在店打工
You could do anything on earth, and you work in a bookstore.
是怎樱
What's that all about?
最起a我^了，  我出去J^了
At least I tried. I went out there and I tried.
我只是以朋友的身份 我l誓是以朋友的身份
Look, I'm just saying this as a friend, and I swear, it's just as a friend,
或S你去で笮┳稍
but maybe you should go out there and, you know, get some help.
去⒓徒』蛑亟ㄈ松之的
Go to rehab or life rehab or something like that.
我不清楚是否有@N|西 但若有的…
I don't even know if they have that sort of thing, but if they did...
好
Okay.
…非常的m合你
...you know, you could be a prime candidate for that.
-我去「重建人生」？ -嗯
-I should go to "life rehab"? -Yeah.
L_我的前院！
Get off my front porch!
艾波？
April?
(BOTTLE SHATTERS)
你f的
You're right.
是很}s，  幔
It is complicated, isn't it?
你郯波，  她曾圻^R卡斯
I mean, you're in love with April, who used to be in love with Lucas,
後凵夏r，  你s巯穆
and then she fell in love with you, but you were in love with Summer,
她s一直壑h普D
who was always really in love with Hampton.
你F在凵习波r，  她又P文
And now that you're in love with April, she's in love with Kevin.
s]有人勰
And no one's in love with you.
很}s
That's complicated.
Yep.
然後呢？
Then what happened?
(THUNDER RUMBLING)
夏G蒂白朗特著《邸
《邸罚  {屋出版，  1943年
Jane Eyre, Random House, 1943.
@版很漂亮，  以美的封面著名
It's a beautiful edition, known for the cover illustration.
但Y面的}~很美，  是中的句子
But there's a really nice dedication inside, with a quote from the book.
「o我的女海  艾波 「人的心充M著[藏的藏
"To my darling daughter, April. 'The human heart has hidden treasures
-「未f的秘密c未打破的沉默中」 -「  「未打破的沉默中
-"'In secret kept, in silence sealed..."' - "'In silence sealed
「  「那些想法、希望、粝搿⒖
"'The thoughts, the hopes the dreams, the pleasures
「  「其魔法⒁蛲嘎抖破解」
"'Whose charms were broken if revealed'
「勰愕母赣H」
"From your loving father."
-嗨，  W莉微雅 -嗨，  威
-Hi, Olivia. -Hi, Will.
-你好幔 -好
-How you been? -Good.
我很久]到你那冗L的道歉了
I haven't heard any of your long sorry messages in a while.
它很棒吧？真是抱歉
Those were delightful, weren't they? Sorry about that.
-艾波在幔 -不，  她去上n
-April here? -No, she's at school.
-上n？ -嗯
-School? -Yeah.
-她在~s大W念T士班 -很好，  W
-She started grad school at NYU. -Great. Wow.
-你若要等她的，  她很快就回砹 -好啊
-If you want to wait, she'll be home soon. -I'd love to.
自己坐，  我得填完@表格
Make yourself comfortable. I have to finish this application I'm writing.
-祝你好\ -x了
-Good luck. -Thanks.
(SIGHS)
嘿
Hey.
你好幔
How you doing?
我是P文
Kevin.
威海s
Will Hayes.
我只是在等艾波
I'm just waiting for April.
你是她前子提的P文幔
Are you the same Kevin that she mentioned a while back?
(PHONE RINGING)
希望是_，  除非她是在收集叫P文的
I hope so. Unless she's collecting Kevins.
P文，  ！
OLIVIA: Kevin, phone!
我M_定我是唯一跟她同居的P文
Anyway, I'm pretty sure I am the only Kevin who's actually living with her.
你知道你要什N了幔
Do you know what you want yet?
-不 -不？
-No. -WAITRESS: No?
威？
Will?
威廉海s？
William Hayes?
天啊
God.
-是你！ -夏曼
-It is! -Summer.
你好美
You look beautiful.
不管你信不信，  我一直想打o你
Believe it or not, I've been meaning to call you.
-我言辛 -你什N？
-I'm pregnant. -You're what?
-真的？ -你相信幔
-Really? -Can you believe it?
-坐下，恭喜你 -xx、xx
-Please, sit. Congratulations. -Thanks. Thanks.
是哪幸\的砘铮
Who's the lucky guy?
-山姆Z斯 -喔
-Sam Knowles. -Okay.
但他基本上已出局了
But he's basically out of the picture.
-他]上榜喔？ -嗯
-He didn't make the cut, huh? -Yeah.
我也不需要男人，  一直都不是很需要
Well, I don't need a guy. I never really did.
你算是最H密的吧
You were about the closest I ever got.
真的，  我跟你在一起r曾想^ 「就是他了」
No, really, when I was with you, I thought, "This is it."
但我搞砸了
But I screwed it up.
-你]有 -我有，  ^τ
-No, you didn't. -I did. I so did.
著
Listen,
我星期天要k小聚
I'm having a little party Sunday.
-我要你 -天啊
-I want you to come. -Oh, boy.
下午四c，  不准不到
4:00. No excuses.
(SIGHING)
你要幔堪萦嘛？
Will you come? Please?
我看看s不s得上
You know, I'll see if I can make it.
-我很希望你 -我到的
-I really want you to. -I'll make it.
我想跟被我害^的人言w於好
I want to make amends with anyone I ever hurt.
我估要花上九月
And I figure it'll take about nine months,
rg上好
which is perfect timing.
-她要走了，  再 -再
-And she's off. Bye. -Bye-bye.
威廉海s
William Hayes.
-爸，  或S@主意不是很好 -什N？
-Dad, maybe this wasn't such a good idea. - What?
跟我f@故事，  @矍乙晒适
Telling me this story, this mystery love story.
-要是我不喜g我怎Nk？ -你然喜g你
-What if I don't like who my mom is? -Of course you'll like who your mom is.
你不用等太久，  因楫晚…
And you don't have to wait long to find out, because that very night...
是夏曼，  ΣΓ慷你不是我生父
It's Summer, isn't it? And you're not my father.
y怪你不想跟她在一起
No wonder you didn't want to be with her.
放pc，雅，  @只是故事
Take it easy, Maya. It's just a story.
而且有快返慕Y局
And this one has a happy ending.
怎N有快方Y局？
How does it have a happy ending?
你跟我，  不管她是l 你要x婚了
You and my mom, whoever she is, you're getting divorced.
有什N好快返模
What's the happy in that?
好吧，  你知道幔课停了
Okay, you know what? I think we should stop now.
不！
No!
肀茶好幔
Then how about a nice cup of tea?
你想的，  我^mv故事，  如何？
If you want, I'll still continue with the story. Does that sound good?
-雅？ -好
-Maya? -Okay.
爸？
Dad?
我真不敢相信你又抽又喝酒 那NS便
I can't believe you smoked and drank and were such a slut.
但我是勰
But I still love you.
(SIGHS)
(KETTLE WHISTLING)
x了
Thanks.
好的、好的
All right. All right.
不、不，  先e吃，要先到我的板凳
No, no. Don't eat it yet! Not till we get to our bench.
你心情不e
You're in a good mood.
我想我墓适轮邪lF了我是l
Well, I think I discovered who my mom is in the story.
-真的？ -真的
-Really? -Really.
-是l？ -不告V你
-Well, who is it? -Not telling.
我最後一次到威廉海sr
So the last time we saw William Hayes,
他lF他的至郏  艾波霍夫曼
he had just discovered that the woman he truly loved, April Hoffman,
凵狭e人
was in love with another man.
(WILLIAM GASPS)
我知道，很
I know. Shocking.
在@期g，  他接受了邀s
Meanwhile, he accepted an invitation
去他前女友夏曼哈德尼家
to the home of his ex-girlfriend, Summer Hartley,
她若真是我，  我就逃去加拿大
who, if she does turn out to be my mother, I'm running away to Canada.
我不是f笑
I'm not kidding.
-他去年走了 -嗯
-He died last year. -Yeah.
-你f了？ -我在《~sr蟆飞嫌锌吹
-You heard? -I read about it in The Times.
-嗯 -嗯
-Yeah. -Yeah.
-天啊，  在k公室Y，  心K病幔 -嗯
-God. Died in his office. Heart attack? -Yeah.
我一直以樗走得很⌒
I always imagined that he'd make a more theatrical exit.
他]f他r 跟系主任的女涸谏嘲l上
What they didn't say was he was on the couch with the dean's daughter.
-老天 -_玩笑的
-Jesus. -I'm kidding.
事上他是一人 好小r後才被工友lF
Actually, he was completely alone and it was hours before the janitor found him.
-要喝c什N？ -抱歉
-You want a drink? -I'm sorry.
-你一定很想念他 -我是啊
-You must miss him. -I do, yeah.
@是o你的
These are for you.
-喔，  威 -嗯
-Oh, Will. -Yeah.
好美
They're beautiful.
你也是
So are you.
-夏曼 -威
-Summer. -Will.
e[我
Don't mess with me.
我知道你想要致
I can see where you're going with this.
再^一，  你就f句迷死人的
In a second, you're gonna say something impossibly charming.
-真的？ -嗯，  很棒
-Really? -Yeah. It's gonna be great.
然後你完全迷倒我 我都知道Y局是什N
And then you're gonna sweep me off my feet and we all know where that's going.
-女孩y道就不能想念男孩幔 -你也知道]好下
-Can't a girl miss a guy? -And you know that's gonna end badly.
她可以
Yeah, she can,
但我真的]rg承受那N痛
but I just don't really have time for the pain.
-不如就略^@些吧？ -好
-So let's just skip all that, why don't we? -Okay.
很公平
Fair enough.
能做朋友幔
Can we be friends?
-好！好 -好
-Yeah! Yeah. -Yeah.
-一言槎ǎ亢 -就@樱  好
-Shake on it? Okay. -Let's do that. All right.
你知道幔
You know what?
我想你人
There's someone here I want you to meet.
嗯，  跟我
Yeah. Come with me.
是我的f
They're an old flame of mine,
我X得你z很聊得
and I think you guys are really gonna, you know, hit it off.
艾蜜莉
Emily.
我把@些插起
I'm gonna put these in some water.
-你看怼 -你看怼
-You look... -You look...
(EMILY CHUCKLING)
你看砗芎
You look great.
-你怎N在~s？ -我住在@
-Why are you in New York? -I live here.
我在市政府教育部做事
I took a job with the city education department.
-我有打o你 -我知道
-I called you. -I know.
-我一直想回你 -_子
-I've been meaning to call you back. -Liar.
-我弄G了你的a -然
-I had lost your number. -Of course.
-是真的，  你知道幔 -威…
-No, it's true. You know what? -Will...
好吧，F在就o我你的
Okay, give me your number, right now.
我R上入我的手CY @泳陀肋h不掉了，  好幔
I'm gonna put it in my cell phone, and that way I'm never gonna lose it, okay?
我的a是212-664-7665
My number is 212-664-7665.
6、6、5，  你看？我入了 F在就不掉了
Six, six, five. See? Now I got it. And I'm never gonna lose it again.
(CELL PHONE RINGING)
-]PS，  接啊 -抱歉
-Oh, no, go ahead, go ahead. -Sorry.
-喂 -喂，  我是威
-Hello. -Hey, it's Will.
我很抱歉弄掉你的
I'm really sorry I lost your number.
我突然有好奇怪的面W^
I just had the weirdest flash of a whole life,
奈窗l生的面
one that never, ever happened.
我怎N了？
What did happen to us?
你跟我的室友上床
-You slept with my roommate. -Oh!
抱歉
I'm sorry.
]e的 是我的「」不是幔
If I remember correctly, I believe it was my "plan," wasn't it?
-那，  得幔 -Γ
-The plan. Remember that? -Yes, the plan.
l@诱f？
Who talks like that?
不，  不是 我只是害怕你c你的粝
No, it wasn't the plan. I was scared of you and your dreams,
然而我分手後，  我好迷失
and then after we broke up, I just felt lost.
我是感到很迷失，  尤其在感情r
I still feel pretty lost, especially when it comes to relationships.
嗯
Yeah.
嗯，  我也…我也是
Yeah, I've been... Me, too.
你有]有想^
Did you ever think
或S我需要的 只是一不同的？
that maybe we just needed a different plan?
等等！停止！倒回去
Wait! Stop! Stop right there. Now, go back.
(REWINDING)
好，  停，  慢速往前
Okay, stop. Now go forward, slowly.
就是@Y
Now here it comes.
那Y！就是那Y！
There! Right there!
就是那！ 我就是因槟才猜到的！
That's it! That's how I figured it out!
我每次不_心r都那幼
That's what Mom does when I'm upset.
她摸摸我的^，要我得很棒
She fluffs up my hair and tells me to be brilliant
或是像太一右眼 每次都我X得好多了
or shine like the sun, and it always makes me feel better.
-硐袷好母H -她是很棒的母H
-Sounds like a great mom. -She is a great mom.
所以你百分百_定艾蜜莉 就是F在朝我走^
So you're absolutely positive, 100%, that Emily is the very same woman
的那女人？
walking toward us right now?
^κ
Absolutely.
是幔
Is it?
-！！ -嘿！
-Mom! Mom! -Hey!
我好高d是你
I'm so glad it's you.
-不然是l？ -l都不是
-Well, who else would it be? -Nobody.
-早安，  威 -嘿，  莎拉
-Good morning, Will. -Hey, Sarah.
，  爸可以跟我一起幔
Mom, can Dad come with us to the zoo?
可以啊，  若爸爸想淼脑
Yeah, if Dad wants to come, sure.
我最喜g游@了，  我去游@吧
You know, I love the zoo. Let's go to the zoo.
-，  你猜怎N樱 -怎樱
-Guess what, Mom? - What?
我昨天在W校W性教育
We learned all about sexual intercourse at school yesterday.
-真的？ -真的
-Really? -Really.
真的
Really.
(PENGUINS CALLING)
我燮簌Z
I love penguins.
我也是
Me, too.
Me, three.
你知道企Z是K身配偶幔
Did you know that penguins mate for life?
m然摩{老跟我f
Although, Mr. Monell told us
有r企Z丈夫c企Z妻子因
that sometimes the husband and wife penguins get separated
它的^痛模式而分_
'cause of their migraine patterns.
-是w徙 -是w徙
-Migratory. -Migratory.
它有r一分_就好啄 但永h都找得到Ψ
Well, sometimes they're apart for years, but they almost always find each other.
你知道企Z夫妻
Do you know what the husband and wife penguins do
找到Ψ结做什N幔
after they find each other after all that time?
㈩^仰起
Throw back their heads,
拍著翅膀大唱歌！
flap their flippers and sing as loud as they can!
(IMITATING PENGUIN CALLS)
(INDISTINCT CHATTERING)
好的，  小鬼^，  走吧！
Okay. All right, munchkin. Let's go!
嘿，  小妖怪，  今天很好玩 我星期三，  好幔
Hey, monster, that was fun today. I'll see you on Wednesday, okay?
(BELLS RINGING)
再_
See you later.
爸！
Dad!
-xx你把故事fo我 -不客
-Thanks for telling me the story. -You're welcome.
-我忘了告V你快返慕Y局了 -是什N？
-I forgot to tell you the happy ending. -What is it?
你啊
You.
(SOBBING)
-嘿，  我勰 -我也勰
-Hey, I love you. -I love you, too.
去找你了，  好幔亢昧耍  再
Go catch up to your mom, okay? All right, bye.
你好幔
Are you all right?
好幔
Yeah?
(SNIFFS)
y先生！嘿，  y先生！
Mr. President! Hey, Mr. President!
威海s 我在92年xr替你做^事
Will Hayes, I worked on the '92 campaign.
(EXHALES)
H特赦M美
嗨，  我找艾波
Hi. I'm looking for April.
得查他有]有法律代表，  好幔
Check that they have legal representation, okay?
-好 -多x，  s翰
-Right. -Thanks, John.
(LAUGHING)
我不敢相信你在做@
I can't believe you're doing this.
-很棒 -xx
-This is great. -Thanks.
-抽？ -戒了
-Still smoking? -I quit.
-我也是，  住在同拥墓寓？ -搬到布克林
-Me, too. Still live in the same loft? -Living in Brooklyn.
永h走在r代尖端
AIways on the cutting edge.
-有男友幔 -目前]有，  你呢？
-Dating? -Not at present. You?
-我x婚了 -我知道
-(WHISPERS) I got divorced. -I know.
我f了，很抱歉
I heard. I'm so sorry.
槭颤N？
Why?
你老是f人太高估婚姻
You always said marriage was overrated.
是啊，  你砭筒宦我的 每次都在I戒指
Yeah, and you never listened to me. You were always with the rings.
-所以你跟P文才]有… -天啊，  P文，  不，  P文…
-Is that why you and Kevin never... -Oh, God, Kevin. No. Kevin...
跟P文是少了什N
Something always seemed to be missing with Kevin.
我不知道
I don't know.
很怪，  但是不太Γ  懂幔
It's weird. It was never quite right. You know?
嗯
Yeah.
-到你真好 -你也是
-It's good to see you. -You, too.
我有|西o你
I have something for you.
(EXCLAIMING)
(APRIL CRYING)
很xx你
Thank you so much.
你怎N找到的？ 我是f，  你在哪找到的？
How did you find it? I mean, where did you find it?
f碓L
That's the difficult part to explain.
@起很糟
This is gonna sound bad.
我找到很久了
I've had it for a while.
多久？
How long?
好啄
Years.
很多年了
Many years.
我是想…
I meant to...
我是打算要o你，  我想要o你
I meant to give it to you. I wanted to give it to you.
只是…
I just...
送不出手，  而我也不知道槭颤N
I couldn』t. And I don't know why.
我有次н^去，  我了，  P文也在…
I dropped it off once. I mean, I tried. Kevin was there and...
嘿，  ]有藉口，  我很抱歉
Hey, there is no excuse, and I'm sorry.
不可原
It's inexcusable.
-你走了，  威 -艾波？
-I think you should go, Will. -April?
你走了
I think you should go.
你]o她？@N久都]o她？
You never gave it to her? After all that time?
-我知道 -那是她爸爸o她的
- I know. I know. -But it was from her dad.
我知道、我知道
I know. I know.
然後你就@幼吡耍
And then you just left?
]e
Yep.
槭颤N除了她之外其他人都化名？
How come you changed all the names except hers?
什N意思？
What do you mean?
故事Y成了艾蜜莉
In the story, you know, like Mom became Emily,
夏曼就是碗sI社 那叫娜塔莎的女人
and Summer's that Natasha lady who writes for that magazine.
但你]有改艾波的名字，  槭颤N？
But you didn't change April』s name. Why?
你槭颤N@些@N感d趣？
Why are you so concerned with all of this anyway?
因槲蚁Ｍ你快
Because I want you to be happy.
你知道
You know,
我很快
I'm happy.
相信我，  爸，  你不快
Trust me, Dad. You're not happy.
去穿大衣
Put your coat on.
-程 -程
-Taxi! -Taxi!
她f跟P文少了什N
She said something was missing with Kevin,
意思就是跟你s]有缺少
which means it might not be missing with you,
-@邮呛檬拢  幔 -可能吧
-which is good news, right? -CouId be.
可能吧
CouId be.
你知道一年Y 有35人跳布克林幔
Did you know that 35 people try to jump off the Brooklyn Bridge each year?
大多是因樾乃
Most because of broken hearts.
我住的
I'll keep that in mind.
(BUZZING)
-哈_ -嘿，  嗨
- Hello. -Hey. Hi.
是我，  威
It's me, Will.
(GASPS)
艾波？
April?
你致铮
What are you doing here?
Uh...
跟她f啊
Go on, tell her.
那是l？
Who's that?
那是我的女海雅
That would be my daughter, Maya.
@硬凰闶亲霰幔你女恚
That's kind of cheating, isn't it? Bringing your daughter?
F在我怎Nk？
What am I supposed to do now?
你可以放我M去啊
Well, you could let us in.
我想她不我M去了
I don't think she's gonna let us in.
(EXHALES)
我X得你e了
I think you're wrong.
恚  我走吧
Come on, let's go. Let's go.
再等一下，  她我M去的
A little while longer. She's going to let us in.
好的，  小鬼^，  @影
Okay, kiddo, here's the deal.
我档30，  好幔
I'm gonna count to 30, okay?
若她不_T，  我就回家了
And if she doesn't let us in, we're gonna go home,
然後以後都e再提起@件事
and we're never gonna talk about this again.
-fh_成幔 -嗯
-DeaI? -Yeah.
浜昧幔
Ready?
-1、2、3… -1、2、3…
-One, two, three... -One, two, three...
-…4、5、6… -…4、5、6…
-...four, five, six... -...four, five, six...
-…14、15、16、17… -…14、15、16、17…
-... 14, 15, 16, 17... -... 14, 15, 16, 17...
她要是我M去 你要像跟我f的一影压适轮vo她
If she lets us in, tell her the story like you told me.
-@铀就知道了 -知道什N？
-And then she'll know. - Know what?
我不解，  反正她就懂了
I can't explain. She'll just know.
-…25、26、27… -…25、26、27…
-...25, 26, 27... -...25, 26, 27...
-29 -29
-Twenty-nine. -Twenty-nine.
29又四分之一
Twenty-nine and a quarter.
29又二分之一
Twenty-nine and a half.
29又四分之三
Twenty-nine and three-quarters.
再砟兀
What comes after that?
走了
Time to go.
但不是@拥
But this wasn't what was supposed to have happened.
-我知道 -我真的以
-I know. -I really thought
她在χvC到我的υ 就放我M去
she would have heard through the intercom and let us in,
或是跑下钦f…
or run down the stairs and say...
什N故事？
What story?
-我留下… -怎樱
-I kept the book... -Yeah?
…是因槟鞘俏H有的凫赌愕|西
...because it was the only thing that I had left of you.
-你一定是雅 -你一定是艾波
-You must be Maya. -You must be April.
然後呢？
So what happens now?
你我M去 然後我f故事o你
You invite us inside, and we tell you the story.
好
Okay.
(UPBEAT FOLK MUSIC PLAYING)